片名：海防最前线
有个传说，说海水下住了个人
There's a legend of a man who lives beneath the sea.
他是捞人的
He is a fisher of men,
是落伍者的最后希望
the last hope of all those who have been left behind.
很多逃生者声称，他们感觉到他的手托在自己身下
Many survivors claim to have felt his gripping hands beneath them,
把自己推上了海面
pushing them up to the surface,
低声鼓励他们，直到救援赶来
whispering strength until help could arrive.
但这，当然，只是个传说
But this, of course, is only a legend.
救命
Help!
在这
Over here!
谢蕊琳
Sherilyn!
救命
Help!
夫人，我是海岸警卫队救生员
Ma'am, I'm a Coast Guard rescue swimmer.
我是来救你的
I'm here to help you.
先生，和你的浮标待在一起 我会回来接你的
Sir, stay with your flotation. I'll be back for you.
- 别丢下我  - 待在那
- Don't leave me!  - Just stay there.
别丢下我
Don't you leave me!
救生篮已经在舱外，正在吊下
Basket is outside the cabin door and going down.
收到
Roger. Copy you.
右前方30尺 右前方15尺
Forward and right 30. Forward and right 15.
右前15尺
Right 15.
停，停
Ho, ho, ho!
救生篮入水了
Basket is in the water.
救生员和生还者已经在篮内了
Swimmer and survivor are at the basket.
让你的头先进去
Put your head in first.
我得出去
I gotta get out!
慢点，向前
Easy, forward.
放开，放开
Let go! Let go.
放开，你会淹死她的
Let go. You're drowning her!
救生员给了他脸上一拳
Swimmer just popped him in the face.
他把男人放进篮里了
Okay, he's putting the man in the basket.
男人进篮了
The man is in the basket.
我们要把他拉上来
We're taking the load.
哇，大浪来袭
Whoa, big wave.
出去，出去，你有毛病啊？
Get out! Get out! What's wrong with you?
坐好，闭嘴
Sit there and shut up.
看到救生员了
Swimmer in sight.
准备拉起
Prepare to take the load.
我看到“可以拉起”的信号了
I have the ready-for-pickup signal.
救生员靠近舱门了
Swimmer is approaching cabin door.
生还者看来失去了意识
Survivor looks unconscious.
救生员在舱内了
Swimmer inside the cabin door.
关上舱门
Cabin door closing.
我想你打断了我的鼻子
I think you just broke my nose.
而你可能杀了你太太，先生
And you may have killed your wife, sir.
20分钟到科迪亚克
Twenty minutes to Kodiak.
收到，他正在对她进行心肺复苏
Roger. He's giving her CPR.
科迪亚克中心，这是海岸警卫队6096号
Comstate Kodiak, this is Coast Guard 6096.
舱内载有两名低体温生还者
We have two hypothermic survivors onboard.
我们20分钟后到
We'll be there in 20 minutes.
请求派救护车到降落地点
Requesting to have an ambulance on-scene when we land.
哇，搞定了
Whoa, there we go.
- 救活她了？  - 救活她了
Got her?  - Got her!
出发啦，伙计
Attaway, baby.
只有死透了…
There's dead,
才算是死
then there's dead.
我发誓，你年岁越大越棒了
I swear, you get better with age.
- 不得不打他，啊？  - 是啊
- Had to hit him, huh?  - Yeah.
你不是，待在那，待那
You are not. You stay over there! You stay over there!
似乎总是强者失控啊
Seems like it's always the big ones that crack.
中尉
Lieutenant.
组员说她沉到水里了 他们以为你救不活她呢
Crew said that she went under. They thought you'd lost her.
幸运吧我猜
Lucky guess.
幸个屁运
Luck, my ass.
- 我不认为你是来真的  - 你当然不了，本
- I didn't think you were serious.  - Of course you didn't, Ben.
你怎么会认为我来真的呢
How could you possibly think I was serious?
我又不是哪个无名的溺水者
I'm not some nameless drowning victim.
哦，天，我很抱歉 救人和我们的社交有冲突
Oh, gee, I'm sorry saving lives doesn't jive with our social...
那
That's...
那是我的椅子
That's my chair.
他说的对，不是那把椅子
Oh, he's right. Not that chair.
对不起，我只是在客厅指了一下 他不知道
I'm sorry. I was just pointing things out in the living room. He didn't know.
我不会拿你的椅子的
I would never take your chair.
搬上去，行吗？
Pick it up, would...
没什么难的，本
Doesn't have to be messy, Ben.
这样简单清楚，对我们双方都是 我们没有孩子
It's clean, simple for both of us. We don't have kids.
那，周五怎么办？
Well, what about Friday?
什么周五怎么办？
What about Friday?
我们要去卡尔和布雷吉特那的
We were gonna go with Carl and Bridget, you know,
那个基地的晚餐舞会
to that dinner-dance thing at the base.
基地？“鸡翅随意吃”？
The base? All-you-can-eat wings?
投飞镖付帐单 这就是我们不能错过的日子？
A dart game to settle the tab? That's the date that we can't break?
- 你是对的，你是对的  - 哇
- You're right. You're right.  - Wow.
听我说，我们离开，好吗？就我们俩
Look, we'll... We'll go away, all right? Just us.
太晚了，本
It's too late, Ben.
我不知道我还有什么没说过的能对你说
I don't know what I can say to you that I haven't said already.
是时候挽救我自己了
95 It's time for me to rescue myself.
可能是我该搬出去
Maybe... Maybe I should be the one to move out.
嗨，这是海伦
Hi, you've reached Helen.
和本的家
And Ben.
请留言
Leave a message.
你甚至不知道这房里的东西在哪
You don't even know where anything is in this house.
还是这样简单的多
It's much easier this way.
二级军士长，请向基地报道
Senior Chief, please report to base.
我能…能改的，我…
I can... I can fix this, all right? I...
我能
I can...
我能改的
I can fix this.
告诉我怎么做
Just tell me what to do.
Tell me what to do.
- 让我走就好  - 不
- Just let me go.  - No.
- 让我走  - 不
你该接的
You should answer that.
6096号救援直升机待命 救生员一号，回基地
Ready rescue helo 6096. Swimmer One, return to base.
- 我不想失去她  - 那就改
- I don't wanna lose her.  - Then change.
本，我们这样的讨论有多少回了
Ben, how many times have we had this conversation?
你唯一的办法就是放弃，去做文职
The only way for you to save it is to give this up and fly a desk.
没错，她只是想过日子
Exactly. She just wants to live.
说不定我们能找个兴趣活动 我们都有兴趣的
Hey, maybe we can get a hobby. Both of us.
比如钓鱼
Something like fishing.
- 钓鱼？  - 是啊
- Fishing?  - Yeah.
我们这样的人不钓鱼，卡尔
Guys like us don't fish, Carl.
这会有用的，一向有用
It'll work out. Always does.
我问你个问题吧，说真的 我现在约她出去是不是太快了？
Let me ask you something, seriously. Is it too soon for me to ask her out?
大概吧
I guess so.
求救！求救！求救！
Mayday! Mayday! Mayday!
这里是大海女王号货船
This is cargo vessel Seaqueen.
我们在北纬55度12分
We're at 55 degrees, 12 minutes north.
西经167度10分
167 degrees, 10 minutes west.
船进水了
We're taking on water.
我们要弃船，重复，弃船
We're abandoning ship. I repeat, abandoning ship.
儿子，看着我，你会没事的，听到吗？
Son, look at me. Look at me. You're gonna be okay. Got that?
听到吗？我们会没事的
Got that? We're gonna be okay.
没事的
Okay.
尾翼除冰警告灯亮了
We have a tail rotor de-ice caution light.
- 有什么相关警告吗？  - 没有
- Any secondaries?  - No.
断路器还在，所以肯定是失效了
Circuit breakers are in, so it definitely has failed,
但那没有什么冰啊
but we're not building up any ice.
- 油量如何？  - 还能撑40分钟
- How's the fuel?  - Forty minutes to bingo.
- 好，接管操纵杆  - 好，接管操纵了
- All right, take the stick.  - Okay, I have the controls.
好啦，现在是暂停时间，各位
All right, huddle time, boys.
除冰误警，油量很低
We have a de-ice fail. We're low on fuel.
手册说我们应该避免我们的损失 你觉得呢，本？
The rulebook says we cut our losses. What do you think, Ben?
我们要是回家，他们就会死，比尔
Well, we go home, they die, Bill.
科迪亚克行动中心，行动中心 这是海岸警卫队6096号
Ops Cent Kodiak, Ops Cent Kodiak, this is Coast Guard 6096.
尾翼除冰警告灯亮了
We have a tail rotor de-ice caution light,
但我们要继续救援
but we are pressing on.
6096号，有情况就向我们汇报
6096, keep us updated on your status.
- 6096号…  - 接通维修部主管
- 6096...  - Get the maintenance chief on the line.
我想知道他对此有何意见
I wanna know what he thinks about this.
计算机说风速在60到85节
Computer's saying the winds are 60 to 85 knots.
我要把你的高度计关掉
I'm turning your bear alt off.
- 你现在靠自己感觉高度了  - 收到
Roger.
低点，低点，右面，水里有残骸
Lower! Lower! Right side. Debris in water.
- 请求打开舱门  - 收到，开舱门
Roger. Open door.
科迪亚克中心，6096号到现场了
Kodiak Ops, 6096 is on-scene.
水里有大量残骸，进行表面搜寻
We have heavy debris in the water. Commencing cover search.
标定并记录位置
Mark and note position.
我要下去了
I'm going in.
他们死了，本，他们死了
They're dead, Ben. Ben, they're dead!
我们并不知道
We don't know that.
有六名落水者，绑在一起 没有生命迹象
There's six PIWs all tied together. No signs of life.
我觉得可能太迟了
I think we may be too late.
不是我们的事，他们在现场 他们会做评估的
Not our call. They're on-scene. They'll make the assessment.
请求下水，长官
Requesting to get wet, sir.
我不是让你去拽尸体的 起码不是这样天气
I ain't sending you fishing for bodies, not in this.
那，救父子呢？
Well, how about fathers and sons?
照明弹，有个活着的，有个活着的
Flare! Flare! We got a live one here. We got a live one!
给你5分钟，然后我们就拉你上来
You got five minutes, then we're hauling your ass back up.
科迪亚克中心，这是海岸警卫队6096号
Kodiak Ops, this is Coast Guard 6096.
水中有人，我们要派出救生员
We have people in the water, and we are deploying our swimmer.
6096号，这是科迪亚克中心，收到
6096, Kodiak Ops, copy.
有个人拿着照明弹，我看不到其他动作
One's holding the flare. I see no other movement.
收到
Roger that.
准备派出救生员
Swimmer's ready to deploy.
- 检查救生员  - 收到，检查救生员
- Check swimmer.  - Roger. Checking swimmer.
救生员全副武装，检查完毕
Swimmer's dressed out. Checklist is complete.
5分钟
Five minutes.
救生员下水了
Swimmer's away.
救生员安全
Swimmer's okay.
- 离开，向左后退30英尺  - 离开，向左后退
- Clear to move back and left 30.  - Clear back and left.
油量如何？
How we looking on fuel there?
还能撑2分钟
Two minutes to bingo.
我是海岸警卫队救生员 来救你的，孩子
I'm a Coast Guard rescue swimmer here to help you, son.
你会没事的，我会把你送上直升机的
You're gonna be okay. I'm gonna get you in that helicopter.
- 看到“可以拉起”的信号了  - 收到
- I have the ready-for-pickup signal.  - Roger.
篮子出舱了
Basket is going out the cabin door.
油量告警了，必须得走了
Bingo. We're at bingo. Gotta go.
小心回来
Ease it back.
- 篮子入水了  - 没时间了，我们得走了，卡尔
- Basket is in the water!  - We're out of time. We gotta go, Carl.
保持位置，稳住
Hold position. Steady. Hold.
他把幸存者放到篮里了
He's putting the survivor in the basket.
你的高度表全乱了
Your rad alt's going crazy.
是啊，我知道，我这一团乱
Yeah, yeah, I know. I'm all over the place.
快点，卡尔，我们现在就得走
Come on, Carl, we gotta go now!
我还没看见“可以拉起”的信号
I don't have a ready-for-pickup signal yet.
哇，卡尔，你后面
Whoa! Carl! Behind you!
糟糕
Holy shit!
尾翼完了
We lost our tail rotor!
求救，求救，求救
Mayday! Mayday! Mayday!
海岸警卫队6096号正在坠落
Coast Guard 6096 is going down!
求救，求救，6096号要入水了
Mayday! Mayday! 6096 is going in.
卡尔，我在这
Carl. I'm here.
卡尔
Carl.
撑住，卡尔，撑住
Hold on, Carl. Hold on.
他们会来救我们的
They'll be coming for us.
我和你在一起，你现在没事了
I got you. You're okay now.
没事的，我在这，卡尔
You're okay. I'm here, Carl.
我们没事的，撑住，我和你一起
We're okay. Hang on. I got you.
- 你觉得他们会来  - 是的，他们回来
You think they're coming?  - Oh, yeah, they're coming.
我要一架C-130立即到事故现场去
I want a C-130 over that crash site now.
克劳斯中尉，执行事故处理程序
Lieutenant Krauss, start the mishap checklist.
遵命，上校
Aye, Captain.
上校，朗道那的幸存者衣服上有 紧急无线电示位标
Captain, I've got an EPIRB hit on Randall's survivor suit.
待命直升机升空，带上救生员
Launch ready helos. Swimmer provide.
有架C-130从阿图岛执行任务刚结束 但油量不足
We have a C-130 coming off a case off Attu. It's already low on fuel.
我不管，让他们关一个引擎
I don't care. Have them cut an engine.
我要让他知道，他不是一个人在那
I want him to know he's not alone out there.
听，听
Listen. Listen.
听见了？
You hear that?
坚持住，卡尔 到了，卡尔，我抓着你呢
Hold on, Carl. Here we go, Carl. I got you.
后备直升机多久能到达
What's the ETA on the backup helo?
正在飞向冷湾
Helo's en route to Cold Bay.
他们有3或4小时就能到现场
They should be on-scene, three, maybe four hours.
那就3小时到
Make it three.
耶稣啊，你觉得我身上中了多少那东西
Jesus. How much more of that stuff do you think I got in me?
感觉到了？
Feel that?
- 感觉到了？  - 是的
- You feel that?  - Yeah.
这就说明你还是活的 我不会放弃的
That means you're alive. I'm not gonna let go.
- 你也别  - 我不会的，不会的
- Don't you!  - I'm not gonna. I'm not gonna.
严重骨折，好像是颈椎
Serious fractures, like in the C-spine,
可能会导致瘫痪
which could cause paralysis.
见到的基本都是旧骨折 手臂和腿部的
Mostly what we see is old fractures in the arms, also in the leg,
但不严重，这次没有新伤，很幸运
but nothing acute. Nothing new with this injury, luckily.
只希望肾脏能起作用
We just hope the kidneys kick in
帮他消除那些积液
and start to help him resolve a lot of that fluid.
非常感谢
Thank you very much.
我们做了很长时间朋友了，对吧？
We've been friends a long time, haven't we?
我一直对你不错，对吧
I've always been good to you, haven't I?
没有让你像其他人一样40岁转文职吧
Didn't promote you to a desk when you turned 40 like everybody else.
是的
That's right.
好，那我现在需要你听我说
All right, so now I need you to listen to me.
好
Okay.
“A”校有一个教师职位的空缺
There's an instructor opening at "A" School, that...
不，答案是不
No. The answer is no.
你刚说你会听的，坐下
You just said you'd listen. Sit down.
我没有兴趣，上校
I'm not interested, Captain.
这不是请求，二级军士长，坐下
Well, it's no longer a request, Senior Chief. Sit down.
你来真的？
You're serious?
你有两个选择
You have two choices.
今天签署文件 以后在科迪亚克过平民生活
Sign the papers today and you can live life as a civilian here in Kodiak,
如果你想的话
if that's what you want.
要不就接受那个“A”校的职位
Or you can take that "A" School opening I'm offering you.
我已经和那的领导讲过了
I've already spoken to command down there.
这个班归你管，你做主
It will be your class. You will be in charge.
你可以利用这段时间让自己恢复健康
You can take the time to work your way back into shape.
我很健康
I am in shape.
妈的，我想说的不是这个
God damn it, that's not what I'm talking about.
本，我只要求你去那几个月
Ben, all I'm asking is that you go down there for a few months.
一边教孩子，一边恢复
You work with the kids, you recharge.
这样你的完美履历才能起好效果
Download that epic resume where it's gonna do some good.
不可能救生员永远是你，本
You can't always be the one in the water, Ben.
当你准备好回来时，你会知道的
You'll know when you're ready to come back.
你们有15秒钟时间下车
You people got 15 seconds to get off this bus.
快，快，赶快下车
Move! Move! Let's go! Get off the bus!
- 快点  - 快走
Hurry up. Let's go, let's go.
把白皮书放红包里
Put your white books in your red bags.
那这些收好，把书收起来
Let's get that squared away now. Put those books away.
女生，提着包，排到队后
Females, grab your bags, fall out to the rear.
跟着佛莱特三级军士长和霍尔上士
Follow Chief Flight and Petty Officer Hall.
剩下人，找一个床位，换上制服
The rest of you, pick a bunk, put on your ODUs.
总共15分钟，还剩下12分钟了
You started with 15 minutes, you are now down to 12.
快走，快点
Move! Move, move, move!
快点，把你们的工作服换下来
Move it out. Get changed out of those working blues.
快点，行动
Hurry up. Move it out.
找好你们的床位，别耽误我时间
Find your rack. Quit wasting my time.
嘿，嘿，那是我的东西，老兄
Hey. Hey! That's my stuff, man.
嘿，那是他的床位
Hey, that's his bunk.
你们是一对吗？
You two a couple?
算了，反正我更喜欢上铺
It's okay. I like the top better anyway.
三万九千名男女
Out of the 39,000 men and women
构成了美国海岸警卫队
who make up the United States Coast Guard,
其中只有280名救生员
there are only 280 rescue swimmers.
快点，快点，美人鱼们
Let's go! Let's go, mermaids!
这是因为我们是海岸警卫队的精英
This is because we are the Coast Guard's elite.
我们是优中选优
We are the best of the best.
当港口因为风暴而关闭时，我们行动
When storms shut down entire ports, we go out.
当飓风把美国海军封在岸上时，我们行动
When hurricanes ground the United States Navy, we go out.
当天主亲自从天堂降临
And when the holy Lord himself reaches down from heaven
摧毁k创造的世界，用风把房屋连根拔起时
and destroys his good work with winds that rip houses off the ground,
我们行动
we go out.
这所学校的淘汰率大大超过50％
And the attrition rate at this school is well over 50%.
所以要是奇迹出现 你真的有资格成为我们中的一员
So if by some miracle you actually have what it takes to become one of us,
那你一生将只拿微薄的薪水
then you get to live a life of meager pay
有很大可能你生命将这样终结 无人相伴，唯有寒冷，慢慢离世
with the distinct possibility of dying slow, cold and alone
陷于茫茫大海之中
somewhere in the vast sea.
但是，你也将获得机会拯救生命
However, you also get the chance to save lives,
而世上再没有比这更好的职业了
and there is no greater calling in the world than that.
那么，女士们先生们，欢迎来到“A”校
So, ladies and gentlemen, welcome. Welcome to "A" School.
有什么问题吗？
Are there any questions?
上校，我是空军士兵费舍尔 只有一个问题
Captain, Airman Fischer. Just have one question.
那个保持所有记录的家伙，他还活着吗？
That guy who holds all them records, is he still alive?
为什么要问
Why do you ask?
我只是想你应该让他知道
I just thought you ought to let him know
我想要让他名字从那块板上消失
I'm about to knock his name off that board.
真的吗？你干嘛不自己告诉他呢？
Really? Why don't you let him know yourself?
他就站在你身后，在屋子后面
He's standing right behind you in the back of the room.
全班都有，向后转 向二级军士长本・朗道致敬
Class, turn around and greet Senior Chief Ben Randall.
二级军士长朗道将在未来18星期中 作你们的班主任
Senior Chief Randall will be your lead instructor for the next 18 weeks.
二级军士长朗道是美国海岸警卫队历史上最出色的救生员之一
Senior Chief Randall is one of the most decorated rescue swimmers
in the history of the United States Coast Guard.
本，你愿意向全班致词吗？
Ben, would you care to address the class?
不，我觉得一天说这么多已经够了
No, I think there's been enough talk for one day.
二级军士长，他们归你管了
Chief Skinner, they're all yours.
全体立正
Attention on deck.
- 稍息  - 是，上校
- Carry on.  - Aye, Captain.
体力测试，明早七点开始
PT test begins at 0700 tomorrow.
全班解散，从前门出去
Class dismissed. You will file through the front door.
第一排先走，第二排跟上
First row first, followed by the second.
佛兰克
Frank.
当上帝把房屋连根拔起时？
"When God rips houses off the ground"?
我有点兴奋
I was rolling.
我不是故意把你名字放那上面的
And I didn't mean to put you on the spot up there.
我对你组员的事情很遗憾
And I was real sorry to hear about your crew.
来吧，我带你转转
Come on. I'll show you around.
- 我听说你现在一个人？  - 对
- So I hear you're staying in a single?  - Yeah.
海伦有些家庭事务要在那处理
Helen's got some family business she's gotta take care of up there.
求救，求救，求救
Mayday, mayday, mayday!
这是博玛雷纳号，博玛雷纳号
This is Ballmariner! Ballmariner!
我们着火了，着火了
We are on fire! We are on fire!
出发
Go!
- 快跑，快跑，快跑  - 快跑
- Let's go, let's go, let's go!  - Let's go, logs.
跑啊，跑啊
Let's move it out! Let's move it out!
相互配合，相互配合
Work as a team! Work as a team!
- 排两行  - 排两行
- Two lines.  - Two lines.
听懂了吗？
Do you understand me?
懂了，霍尔上士
Yes, Petty Officer Hall.
很好，我们来试试，俯卧撑
Very well, let's try it. Lean and rest!
起来
Pop tall.
乌拉
Oorah!
- 这他妈的成什么样子  - 太差了
What the hell was that?  - HALL: That was terrible.
没见过更差的
That was the worst I've ever seen.
太差了
That was terrible.
再试一遍
Let's try that again.
- 二十二  - 加油
Twenty-two. Come on!
- 上  - 二十三
- Up!  - Twenty-three.
下，上
Down. Up.
- 二十四  - 屁股下去，小子
- Twenty-four.  - Get that ass down, Cable!
- 上  - 二十五
- Up!  - Twenty-five.
实在太差了
That is absolutely horrible.
起来跑到松树那再回来，出发
Pop tall to the lone pine and back! Go!
快跑，动起来，出发
Move your ass! Let's move it! Get it going!
快跑
Let's go.
让他们回来
Bring them back.
- 回来  - 快跑，回去
Circle back!  - HALL: Let's go! Get back here!
- 回来站队  - 快点
Get back in line!  - INSTRUCTOR: Let's move!
- 站好队  - 快跑，快，快
- Back in formation.  - Let's move, move, move!
站好队
Back in formation.
俯卧撑姿势，二级军士长来检查
Lean and rest. Senior Chief on deck.
起来
Pop tall.
乌拉
Oorah!
我不在乎你是谁
I don't care who you are,
从哪来，到哪去
where you are from or where you are going.
我只在乎一件事
I care about one thing and one thing only.
就是将来要求你们救的人
That is the future victims that you will be asked to save.
如果我觉得你救不了他们 我就会开除你，懂了吗？
If I feel that you will fail them, I will fail you, understood?
明白，二级军士长
Yes, Senior Chief!
霍吉，你从哪来？
Hodge. Where are you from, Hodge?
我来自新泽西州提奈克 二级军士长!
I'm from Teaneck, New Jersey, Senior Chief!
霍吉这是第三次尝试了
Hodge is our triple repeat.
你这回打算通过吗？三进宫？
Do you plan on making it this time, threepeat?
我真的希望可以，二级军士长
I really hope to, Senior Chief.
好，不过，希望不能让你浮起来，霍吉
Yeah, well, hope don't float, Hodge.
你最好开始学习逆流而游而不是顺流而下
You better start to learn to swim against the current and not with it.
遵命，二级军士长
Aye, aye, Senior Chief.
费舍
Fisch.
费舍，你为什么要来？
Fisch. Why are you here, Fisch?
我要来超出你的预期 二级军士长
I'm here to exceed your expectations, Senior Chief.
我从心底就是救生员 生来如此，水中长大，乌拉
I'm a rescue swimmer at heart, born, bred and water-fed. Oorah!
哇，我猜你整个早上都在练这个吧
Wow. I bet you practiced that all morning.
费舍尔是高中游泳冠军
Mr. Fischer is our high school swim champ.
他拿到了常春藤所有学校的奖学金
He's had scholarships to every lvy League.
哦，对不起，我没意识到他这么合格
Oh, I'm sorry. I didn't realize that he was so qualified.
我是说，你在池子里创造记录吗？
I mean, you set records in a pool?
太棒了
That's amazing.
我猜最深的地方大概有八尺深吧？
I'll bet it was like, what, eight feet deep in the deep end?
要是你的鼻塞不起作用怎么办？
What if your nose plug didn't work?
如果其他救生员占了你的泳道呢？
What if another swimmer had cut into your lane?
看在上帝份上，你可能会死的
For the love of God, you could have been killed.
你们日程上安排你们今早进行体力测试
Your schedule says that you will perform a PT test this morning.
这没有必要
That will not be necessary.
你们被召来在水中服役
Water is where you've been called to serve.
那你们就在水里测试好了
Water is where you will be tested.
这将替代你们的体力测试
This will serve in place of your PT in-test.
考试结果只有通过或不通过
This is a golno-go exercise.
你们要踩水一个小时
You will tread water for one hour.
你碰了墙，不通过 碰了底，不通过
You touch the wall, you fail. You touch the bottom, you fail.
不通过就回家
You fail and you go home.
军士长，本校执行的是两次不通过制度
Senior, this school operates on a two-challenge rule.
你不能第一天就开除人啊
You can't throw them out on their first day.
如果你在暖水池都撑不过去
If you cannot survive in a warm pool of water,
这就没你什么事了，全班明白了吗？
then you have no business being here. Does this class understand?
明白，二级军士长
Yes, Senior Chief!
乌拉，5506班
Oorah, Class 5506.
谁能告诉我救生员的座右铭
Now, who here can tell me the rescue swimmer's motto?
“舍己为人”，二级军士长
"So others may live," Senior Chief!
喔，我觉得安全点了
Oh, I feel safer already.
你愿意牺牲自己让他人活下去吗？金鱼？
You willing to sacrifice your life so others may live, Goldfish?
是的，二级军士长
Yes, I am, Senior Chief.
那你得正确努力 我要你们所有人都好好想想这个
You will have to earn that right. I want all of you to think about that.
总有这样的时候
There's going to come a time
你们会筋疲力尽，想要放弃了
when you reach the point of exhaustion and you wanna give up.
问题是，你们会不会
Question is, will you?
有三个字母能让你解脱
There are three letters that will set you free.
DOR，自愿退出
DOR. Drop on Request.
看看那
Look at that.
浪费时间
Waste of time.
- 你还好吗？  - 嘿，加油，待在上面
- You all right?  - Hey. Come on, stay up.
谁帮帮他
Somebody help him out.
嘿，他沉下去了
Hey, he's going under, man!
帮帮他
Help him out.
快啊
Come on!
- 帮帮他  - 帮帮他
- Help him out.  - Help him out!
嘿，放松点，伙计
Guys, relax, man!
加油啊
Come on.
加油
Come on, man.
你被开除了
You're dismissed.
- 我肌肉痉挛了  - 你死了
- I cramped up.  - You're gone.
走吧，里昂，出来，快点
Let's go, Lyons, out of the water. Hurry up.
- 快点  - 快点
Let's go.
站起来
On your feet.
物理学第一课，各位： 有肌肉并不会浮起来
First lesson in physics, people: Muscle does not float.
沃特森上士，让他们出池子
Petty Officer Watson, pull them out of the pool.
遵命，二级军士长
Aye, aye, Senior Chief.
快点，出池子
Let's go, people, out of the water.
快点，动起来
Hurry up! Let's move, people!
快点，快点
Hurry up! Hurry up!
版主，来这
Class leader, right here.
我以为你说你愿意牺牲自己救他人的
I thought you said you were willing to sacrifice your life for another.
是的，二级军士长
I am, Senior Chief.
那他向你求救时，干嘛不救自己的队友
Then why didn't you save your teammate when he reached out for you?
我没意识到我们是整队合作的，二级军士长
I wasn't aware we were working as a team, Senior Chief.
这是我们唯一的工作方式，游泳冠军
That's the only way we work, swim champ.
明白，二级军士长
Aye, aye, Senior Chief.
混蛋
Asshole.
- 再说一遍  - 你听见我说的了
- Come again?  - You heard me.
嘿，嘿，别动手
Hey, hey, hey! Ease up! Ease up!
- 不值得  - 别
- It's not worth it.  - Come on.
有个好消息，里昂 我的浮标维护船上有个空缺
Good news, Lyons. I think there's an opening on my buoy tender.
我帮你推荐一下吧
I'll put in a word for you, huh?
我会怀念那家伙的
I'm really gonna miss that guy.
- 嘿，伙计，你干嘛？  - 你得回自己的铺位了
- Hey, man, what are you doing?  - Got your bunk back.
- 上校  - 本，进来
Ben. Come in.
你干的太快了
You work fast.
里昂是我们最佳候选人之一
Lyons, he was one of our top candidates.
有时你还得射杀人质呢
Sometimes you gotta shoot a hostage.
嘿，我们都知道你是传奇人物
Look, we all know that you're a legend and all,
但我们的课程已经被证实很有效果
but our program has been proven to work.
训练和实际之间是有差距的，狂犬
There's a gap between training and what really happens out there, Cujo.
- 哦，真的？  - 没错
- Oh, really?  - That's right.
我的目的就是要缩小这个差距
My intention is to narrow that gap.
如果有谁有不同意见
Now, if someone has a problem with that idea,
我洗耳恭听
I'd like to hear about it.
这就是我们要做的吗？长官
Is this how it's gonna be, sir?
没错
Yes, it is.
- 请求离开，长官  - 批准
Permission to be dismissed, sir?  - CAPTAIN: Granted.
快走，快走，靠紧
Let's go. Let's go. Keep it together. Look tight!
靠紧，快走，动起来
Keep it together. Let's go. Let's move.
你们有三分钟穿好装备，全部装备
You've got three minutes to get this gear on. All of it.
预备，开始
Set! Go!
快
Let's go.
准备好了吗？
Are you ready?
加油，救生员
Come on, rescue swimmer!
别放弃
Don't quit on me.
听见了吗？
Do you hear me?
起来，起来
Pop tall! Pop tall! Pop tall!
如果你犯了个错，就认错 吸取教训继续
If you make a mistake, just fess up to it. Take your licks and we'll press on.
每个人都会为笨嘴付出代价
Everybody now is gonna pay for your potty mouth.
- 下，上  - 一
-Down. Up  - One!
下
Down.
- 上  - 三
- Up  - Three!
下，上
Down. Up.
五，六
Five! Six!
- 继续  - 七
- Forward.  - Seven!
你疯了吗？
Are you crazy?
我是指挥官，起来
I'm the commander! Get up!
- 乌拉  - 趴下，趴下
Oorah!  - Get down! Get down!
乌拉
Oorah!
下去
Go.
乌拉
Oorah.
Oorah!
氯气中毒会死吗？
Can you die from chlorine poisoning?
我都感觉不到自己的腿了，我是说真的
I can't feel my legs. I'm serious.
我不知道你们怎样，但是我感觉不错
I don't know about you guys, but I feel good.
这个叫朗道的，完全不按规矩来
This Randall guy, he's operating on some whole other cylinder.
这算啥，两个星期 他差不多都开除了一半人了
What is it, two weeks, and he's failed almost half the class already?
他是传奇人物
He's a legend.
他们说他救过两百多人
They say he's got something like 200 saves.
我听说是三百
I heard it was 300.
谁管他救过多少？
Who cares what his number is?
他要是这么牛，来这干嘛
If he's such a stud, what's he doing here?
大家感觉如何啊
How we feeling, boys?
嘿，Z，你要去哪？
Hey, Z, where you going?
我姐姐最好的朋友要结婚了
My sister's best friend is getting married,
他们要在城里搞个大仪式
and they're having a big reception downtown.
我答应她我会去的
I promised her I'd go.
等等，你是说结婚典礼？
Wait, you said wedding reception?
- 恭喜  - 谢谢
- Congratulations.  - Thanks.
嗨
Hi.
- 恭喜  - 嗨
- Congratulations.  - Hi.
很高兴见到你
Nice to meet you.
是的，阿拉斯加州科迪亚克 海伦・朗道的号码
Yes, Kodiak, Alaska. The number for Helen Randall.
好，那试试海伦・佛里曼
Okay, try Helen Freeman.
没错
You betcha.
我是海伦，请留言
Hi, you've reached Helen. Leave a message.
海伦，我是本，天，这太奇怪了
Helen, it's Ben. Jesus, that was weird.
从我们长大就没用过你的娘家姓
Haven't had to use your maiden name since we were kids.
海伦，如果你在，请接我电话 我们得谈谈
Helen, if you're there, just pick up. We need to talk.
求你了
Please.
好吧，好吧
All right. All right.
敬失败者，敬通过第一阶段测试的
To those who have fallen, to those who have survived Phase 1.
- 干杯  - 干杯
Cheers.
- 乌拉，乌拉，乌拉  - 各位，这太棒了
- Oorah, oorah, oorah.  - Guys, this is great.
敬我们的女神琳茜，你任何时候都可以救我
And to our gal Lindsey. You can rescue me anytime.
- 他真说了？  - 你没说过
- Did he just say that?  - You did not just say that.
你知道吗，杜伦，我觉得我可能会让你淹死
You know what, Doran? You, I think I might actually let drown.
喔
Oh!
嘿，二级军士长
Hey, Senior Chief.
本，她今晚很辣啊
Ben, she's hot tonight.
这地方没变
This place has not changed.
- 来自阿拉斯加州科迪亚克  - 别
- From Kodiak, Alaska...  - Don't.
二级军士长本・朗道
...Senior Chief Ben Randall is in the house,
平安无事，还活着
big as day and still alive.
我一定欠了谁钱了
I must owe somebody money.
- 你太坏了  - 哦，本
- You're terrible.  - Oh, Ben.
有谣言说你要在城里教书啊
I heard a rumor you were gonna be teaching here in town.
这要不是命运，我都不知道还能是什么
If that ain't the karmic wheel spinning, I don't know what is.
好啦，敬回头的浪子
Well. To the prodigal's return.
- 你的另一半呢？  - 她决定待在家
- Where's your better half?  - She decided to stay home.
- 哦  - 工作的事情
- Oh.  - Work stuff.
是啊，科迪亚克的冬天 让我看看，路易斯安娜的冬天
Yeah. Winter in Kodiak. Let me see. Winter in Louisiana.
- 好啦，别说了  - 她决定待在家
- All right, stop. Stop.  - "She decided to stay home."
好事情是我们还有整瓶酒和半个晚上
Well, it's a good thing we got a full bottle and half the night.
没错
Yes, we do.
看看，她盯着你看呢
Check it out. She's staring at you.
那个女孩没盯着我看
That girl right there is not staring at me.
你用手指她了
Did you just point at her?
- 她看见你指她了吗？  - 我不知道
- Did she see you point?  - I don't know.
好啦，你得去跟她谈谈，你得主动
All right, now you gotta go talk to her. You gotta go make a move.
- 没错  - 我不行
- Yeah.  - I can't.
我现在不想和女人聊天
I just don't feel comfortable right now talking to women.
你想告诉我你愿意跳出直升机
You're telling me you wanna jump out of helicopters
- 去救人  - 你和我聊了
- for a living...  - You're talking to me.
但不愿意和女孩聊天？
...but you can't go talk to a girl?
- 没错，这就是我想说的  - 真能说会道啊
- That's exactly what I was telling you.  - You're smooth.
好啦，我来帮帮你
All right, look, I'm gonna help you out here.
我给你演示一下怎么做
I'll show you how it's done.
找这里最辣的妞，我会带她回家
Pick out the hottest girl in here. I'll take her home.
- 哦，天啊  - 好啊
- Oh, gosh.  - Okay.
- 他又来了  - 不，我来选妞如何？
- Here he go, now.  - No, how about I will find the girl?
行啊
All right.
- 好  - 你觉得哪一个？
- Okey-doke.  - Who you thinking?
一定要辣
Make sure she's hot.
- 你看哪呢？  - 好
- Where you looking?  - Okay.
吧台那里，两点钟方向
At the bar. Two o'clock.
- 不错  - 那个不错
- Yes.  - That's a good one.
她不可能和你聊的
There's no way in hell she's talking to you.
- 那一个？  - 没错，那个
- That one?  - Yeah, that one.
我出一百美元，她一分钟就会把你拒了
Hundred bucks says she shuts you down in less than a minute.
喔
Boom.
- 我看这好像赌注啊，杰克  - 是赌注
- That looks like a bet to me, Jake.  - That's a bet.
好啦，好啦
All right. All right.
一百美元，我一分钟就能把她搞上手
Hundred bucks says I close in less than a minute.
哦，没问题
Oh, absolutely.
- 向你致敬，伙计  - 嘀哒，嘀哒，嘀哒
- Hats off, man.  - Tick-tock. Tick-tock. Tick-tock.
从我和她说话开始
Clock starts when I talk to her.
没问题
That's fine.
绝对让人尴尬
This is gonna be embarrassing.
好啦，伙计
All right, buddy.
你觉得怎样？
What do you think? What do you got?
- 你觉得他能做到吗？  - 是的
You think he's gonna do it?  - CADET 2: Yeah.
晚安，女士，我可以给你买杯酒吗？
Evening, ma'am. Can I buy you a drink?
这样不好吧
I don't think so.
你不会知道自己错过了什么
You don't know what you're missing.
你肯定要玩这套吗？
You sure you wanna go with that one?
说你最棒啦，什么都玩的转啦
That's, like, your top-of-the-line, A-game material?
依我看，你有两个选择
See, the way I see it, you got two choices here:
离开我这里
Walk away from me,
或者和我一起离开，我们平分那钱
or walk out of here with me and split the cash.
钱？
Cash?
什么钱？
What cash?
你和你朋友赌的说你能吊到我的
The money you bet your friends you could pick me up.
嘿，那让我很紧张啊
See, that makes me nervous.
她正在拒绝他呢
She's shutting him down.
你还有多少时间？
How much time you got left?
- 大概20秒钟  - 走吧？
- About 20 seconds.  - Shall we?
- 哦，天啊  - 不可能
Oh, my gosh.  - No way.
看起来他们好像要一起离开酒吧啊
It looks like they're leaving the bar together, is what I see.
不可能
No way!
一定是蒙我
You have got to be kidding me.
- 难以置信  - 他怎么做到的？
- Unbelievable.  - How did he do that?
- 我被震住了  - 我被震住了
- I'm impressed.  - I'm impressed.
你基地外面有个酒吧叫玛吉，你知道吗？
There's a bar outside your base called Maggie's. You know it?
知道
Yeah.
好，下周五8点在那见我
Good. Meet me there next Friday around 8:00?
- 你有名字吗？  - 有
- You got a name?  - Yeah.
别忘带我的钱
Don't forget my money.
有中名吗？
You got a middle name?
你该意识到我回不去那吧
You do realize I can't go back in there.
这是死神的敲门声
This is the sound of death knocking.
搜救警报和缺梦少觉是…
SAR alarms and sleep deprivation are part...
他们到底跑哪去了？
Where the hell are they?
知道吗，低温病的第一阶段是最关键的
You know, the first stages of hypothermia are the most critical.
为什么
Why?
因为你还有能力想，跟我说
Because you still have the ability to think. Say it.
你还有能力想
You still have the ability to think.
你在这个阶段做出的决定
The decisions you make during this stage
将决定你的生死
are gonna determine whether you live or die.
有什么理由你不呼吸吗？金鱼？
There a reason you're not breathing, Goldfish?
有什么理由你不呼吸吗
Is there a reason why you're not breathing?
我不知道谁不呼吸15分钟还能活
I don't know anyone who can stay alive without breathing
二级军士长
for 15 minutes, Senior Chief.
你是验尸官吗？
Are you a coroner?
宣告他人死亡可没在我们的工作介绍上啊
Because pronouncing people dead is not part of our job description.
我们总说什么？
What do we always say?
死透了才是死
There's dead and then there's dead.
我们从不停止，杰克 不管是机舱里还是停机坪上
We never stop, Jake, not from the cabin to the tarmac.
- 我们从不停止  - 明白，二级军士长
- We never stop.  - Aye, aye, Senior Chief.
- 懂了吗？  - 懂了，二级军士长
Understood?  - CADETS: Yes, Senior Chief.
好，杰克，回池子里来，霍吉，你上去
Okay, Jake, in the pool. Hodge, you're up.
你来和假人演习
You're with the dummy.
好，现在，三个字
All right, now. Three letters.
说那三个字你就能拿到一杯热咖啡，还有毯子
Three letters will get you people a cup of hot coffee and a blanket.
你怎么说，金鱼？
What do you say, Goldfish?
其实我不那么冷了，二级军士长
I'm actually not that cold anymore, Senior Chief.
你不冷了，是因为你的血在流动
You're not cold anymore because blood is moving
从四肢流回心脏
from your outer extremities to your heart.
因此你的胳膊动不了了
That's why your arms won't work.
你该计划好，你事业的60％时间
You can plan on spending roughly 60% of your career
你将处在轻度低温病状态
in a mildly hypothermic state.
二级军士长，我可以说句话吗？
Senior Chief, may I have a word?
长官？
Sir?
我怎么没得到通知？我们有教室的
Why wasn't I informed of this? You know, we have classrooms.
你的职责只是教他们低温病的各个阶段
Your assignment is to simply teach the stages of hypothermia.
长官，再过大概两分半，他们就会理解的
Sir, in about two and a half minutes, they'll understand.
请求继续，长官
Permission to carry on, sir?
继续吧
Go ahead.
三个字，各位，你就能拿到一杯热咖啡 还有温暖的毯子
Three letters, people, will get you a hot cup of coffee and a warm blanket.
你们怎么办，5506班
What do you say, Class 5506?
乌拉
Oorah.
这是缺氧存活训练
This is an oxygen-deprivation anaerobic exercise.
你和你的同伴要推一块砖头
You and your partner will push your brick
沿着游泳池底，推过去再推回来
along the bottom of the pool, down and back.
如果你需要换气，你可以上浮，换一口气
If you need air, you may surface. One breath.
你的同伴必须待在水下，直到你回来
Your partner must remain underwater until you return.
只有你们两个都碰到砖头时，才能推它
Your brick can only move while both of you are touching it.
如果你们一起浮上来，你们一起失败
If you both surface, you both fail.
这个训练旨在教你们如何合作
This exercise is designed to teach you teamwork.
听我哨音，脱掉装备，成对进池
On my whistle, drop your gear, enter the pool and pair up.
我说换一口气，小子，快下去
I said one breath, Sunkist. Let's go!
- 我不行了  - 快点
- I can't.  - Come on!
- 我不行  - “不行”
- I can't.  - "I can't."
滚出池子去，快点
Get your ass out of the pool! Let's go!
快点，俯卧撑姿势
Come on! Lean and rest.
你想退出，退出吧，我可以换点新人
You wanna quit, just quit now. I could use those new shoes.
二级军士长，出事了
Senior Chief, we got a problem.
有人失踪了
Somebody's missing.
耶稣基督啊
Jesus Christ.
要有新记录了，乌拉
That's gotta be a new record. Oorah.
我烦透记录了，把他弄上来
I'm so sick of records. Go get him.
你觉得我会因为你能憋气而震撼吗？金鱼
You think I'm impressed because you can hold your breath, Goldfish?
我不知道什么能让你震撼，二级军士长
I wouldn't venture to say what would impress you, Senior Chief.
好啦，让他出池子，今天到此为止
All right. Get him out of the pool. We're done for the day.
出池子，费舍尔，快点
Out of the pool, Fischer. Let's move.
- 乌拉  - 快点
- Oorah!  - Move your ass.
起来，小子
Pop tall, Sunkist.
出池，出池
Out of the pool. Out of the pool.
记录
Records.
绝不要盯着火焰看，各位
Never stare directly into the flame, people.
会损害你的夜晚视力的
It will impair your night vision.
这是马克58型闪光弹，看起来就这样
This is a Mark 58 flare. This is what it looks like.
这能照亮50尺宽的一片水
It'll light up a 50-foot swath of water
用红外线可以在几英里外测到
and can be detected by infrared miles out.
这是用来演示的
This is a demonstration model.
正常的可以燃40到60分钟
The normal one will burn for 40 to 60 minutes.
注意
Hey, pay attention.
马克58时用来标示风向和水流向的
The Mark 58 is used to reference the wind, to detect a current.
沃特森上士将会给你们详细讲一下
Petty Officer Watson is gonna talk a little bit more about that.
五分钟
Five minutes.
你看到的这条船
The vessel you're looking at right now,
正在向左舷倾侧
people, is listing to the port side.
作为救生员，到了直升机门那
As a rescue swimmer, when you get to the door of the helicopter,
你得看下面，注意
you need to look down and pay attention
看下面到底有什么情况
to what you really have down there.
知道自己能力的极限是非常重要的
It's very important that you understand your limitations.
不知道，你就会死
Limitations without understanding are gonna get you killed.
在这起事件中，船陷在 白令海峡中的大堆冰块里了
Case in point, this vessel's trapped in pancake ice in the Bering Sea.
你们能看到，船员上了甲板
And as you can see, the crew are out on the deck
在一个容易起吊的位置
in a relatively manageable hoisting position.
但忽然之间
But suddenly...
那些冰块的重量高达几千磅
Those pieces of ice can weigh in upwards of thousands of pounds.
想象一下被2000磅重的冰块挤压的情况下
Now imagine yourself trapped in between 2,000-pound pieces of ice
还要游泳的感觉
trying to free-swim.
谢谢，军事长
Thank you, Chief.
下一节，沃特森上士
Next scenario, Petty Officer Watson.
在你离开直升机，跳下…
Before you leave that helicopter, going down to a...
标准化能确保我们 在卡特里娜飓风影响下成功行动
Standardization is one of the reasons we were so successful during Katrina.
我们的同事来自全国各地
We had crews come in from all over the country,
但这没关系 因为我们接受的都是相同的训练
but it didn't matter, because we have all been trained the same way.
我不认识驾驶员，不认识副驾驶
I didn't know my pilot, I didn't know my copilot,
我不认识机师，但有什么关系呢？
I didn't know my flight mechanic. But guess what?
这都无关紧要，因为…
It didn't matter, because...
我们干的就是这个
That's why we do it.
因此你们要把注意力集中在这上面
So you have to get your mind wrapped around that idea.
当直升机飞过来的时候 当起风的时候
When that helicopter starts going, when the wind starts coming...
- 二十  - 下!上!
Twenty! Down! Up!
- 二十一  - 下!上!
- Twenty-one!  - Down! Up!
- 二是二  - 下!上!
- Twenty-two!  - Down! Up!
二十三
Twenty-three!
- 二  - 下!
- Two!  - Down!
- 上!  - 三
- Up!  - Three!
不要陆地 不要森林
Don't need no land Don't need no tree
我要去的是水里
Out in the water That's where I wanna be
- 嘿，来杯啤酒怎么样？  - 没问题
Hey, Mags, can I have a beer?  - MAGGIE: Sure.
好啊好啊
Well, well.
终于答应跟我喝一杯了
So you are gonna have a drink with me.
不，我是在你旁边喝 完全两码事
No, I'm having a drink near you. Entirely different thing.
你从来就这样冷淡吗？
You're a regular lightning rod, aren't you?
- 你叫什么名字？  - 戴茜・布克南
- What's your name?  - Daisy Buchanan.
你在说谎，戴茜・布克南
You're lying, Daisy Buchanan.
- 有这个可能性  - 不
- There is that possibility.  - No.
这一定是谎话
That was a sure-fire lie.
我想你是读过伟大的盖茨比了
So I take it you've read The Great Gatsby.
- 我的钱呢？  - 我没带在身上
- Where's my money?  - It's not on me.
但是很接近了，在一个安全的地方
But it is close. In a very safe place.
我画了张地图，里面有很复杂的线索
Now, I've drawn a map with a complex set of clues.
每一步都比前一步难很多
Each one is more fiendishly clever than the last.
好吧，这样也成
That works, too.
这只是你裤子的图片而已
This is just a picture of your pants.
是的，画的不好，但线索真的很难
Yeah, but it's a bad picture, which is what makes it so fiendishly clever.
不错
Nice.
为什么艾米丽・托马斯会成为教师呢？
How did Emily Thomas become a schoolteacher?
为什么杰克・费舍尔会成为
Well, how does Jake Fischer become a guy
想从直升机上跳下去的人呢？
who wants to jump out of helicopters?
我干掉很多家伙，要找个地方躲起来
I killed a couple guys and had to get out of Dodge.
- 你在说谎  - 有这个可能性
- You're lying.  - There is that possibility.
说实话
The truth.
我的牛仔生涯以失败告终了
My bull-riding career was going down the drain.
- 比刚才有长进  - 好吧，到你了
- Okay, that's better.  - All right, now you.
我真的得走了
I really should go.
走？什么？不，别走
Go? What? No, you're not going.
我们刚开始找到点乐趣 你侮辱了我的画
We're just starting to have fun. You're insulting my drawing.
不，你自己侮辱了你的画
No, you were insulting your drawing.
虽然，这是个很失败的画
Although, to be fair, it's a pretty lame drawing.
好吧，你还不能走 因为你欠我一支舞
All right. Well, you can't go, 'cause you owe me a dance.
不，才没有呢
No, I don't think so.
好吧，那我要拿回我的钱
Well, then, I'm gonna have to take that money back,
因为我觉得我不该得到这钱…
'cause I wouldn't feel right taking the money...
听着，每18周，都有一批新的学员到来
Look, every 18 weeks, a new bunch of you guys comes in,
都想得到女生的青睐
all looking to score with the local talent.
我住这儿，我在这儿工作
I live here. I work here.
我只是请你跳一支舞
It's a good thing I'm just asking for a dance, then.
好吧，一支舞
Okay, one dance.
没有附加条件，临时的
No attachments. Just casual.
我是个男人，我知道什么是临时的
I'm a guy. I can do casual.
好吧
Mmm-hmm.
我最拿手的就是临时
I am the king of casual.
只是还有一件事
There's just one thing, though.
你必须停下那种让我脱掉衣服的目光
You're gonna have to stop undressing me with your eyes,
因为你可没本事把我搞上床
'cause there's no way you're getting me into bed.
嘿
Hey, you.
我得去上班了
I gotta get to work.
- 我迟到了，睡过头了  - 什么
- I'm late. I fell asleep.  - What...
- 他们会杀了我的  - 他们不会的
- They're gonna kill me.  - They won't kill you.
这和学校不一样
This isn't like school.
军队里可不会手下留情
They don't hand out tardies in the military.
- 你闻起来好香  - 我闻起来像你的味道
- You smell really good.  - I smell like you.
- 他还没回来？  - 没有
- He never came back?  - Nope.
哇
Wow.
我当教官的4年里还没有过队员出走
Four years as lead instructor, I never had one go missing.
好吧，带其它人去泳池，这里交给我
All right, take the others to the pool. I'll catch up.
是，长官
Aye, aye, Senior.
天啊，他们来了 停，停车
Oh, God, there they are. Stop. Stop the car. Stop.
- 就停这里？  - 是的
- Here?  - Yes.
- 好的  - 我会打电话给你的
- Okay.  - I'll call you.
最好如此，再见
You better. Bye.
杰克!杰克!杰克!
Jake! Jake! Jake!
飞行员费舍尔迟到了
Airman Fischer's coming in late, yeah
给
Here.
飞行员费舍尔迟到了
Airman Fischer's coming in late, yeah
嗨
Hi.
出去约会一定很快活
Must be nice to go out on a date, yeah
天啊，看这个
Oh, my goodness, look at this.
看这个 “费舍尔带队取得州冠军”
Look at this. "Freshman Leads Team to State Title."
这是你
That's you.
天啊
Holy smokes.
“16岁的杰克・费舍尔 已经成为成熟的运动员”
"At only 16, Jake Fischer displays the traits of a seasoned athlete.
“有一件事是确定的： 这个年轻人有很美好的未来”
The future looks bright for this young competitor."
我猜他们不知道你会被“A”学校退学
Guess they didn't know you were gonna flunk out of "A" School.
昨晚过的不错吧？
You have a nice evening?
把衣服换好
Get dressed.
看来还要再加一块砖头 搬砖头
Think we need another brick. Bring it in.
金鱼
Goldfish.
感谢由于费舍尔先生的课外活动
Thanks to Mr. Fischer's extracurricular activities,
你们36小时不准睡觉
you have all now gone 36 hours without sleep.
吹哨
Blow it.
班长，你们完工了 去浅水区列队
Class leader, you are done. Form it up in the shallow end.
是，二级军士长!
Aye, Senior Chief!
5506班，列队!
Class 5506, form it up!
不不不，你跟着我
No. No, no, no. You're with me.
我是个救生员，是的，我是
I'm a rescue swimmer, yes, I am
我来这里援救你们离开这该死的地方
I'm here to pull your ass out of this jam
我跳出直升机，带着绳索
I jump from the helo and swing from the cable
好了，停下
All right, knock it off.
处理你还真不容易，费舍尔
I am having a hard time figuring you out, Fischer.
我想你喜欢看到自己登报的照片
I mean, you like seeing your picture in the paper.
看上去无上的荣耀，也许边上 还有几个小妞，我说的对吗？
In it for the glory, maybe a few chicks. Am I right?
但来这里以后
But when it comes down to it,
你必须超越从前
you will choose yourself over them every time,
就像你第一天在池子里的那样
like you did on the first day in the pool,
就像你昨天缺席集合那样
like you did yesterday by missing muster.
不会再发生这样的事了，二级军士长!
Won't happen again, Senior Chief!
你为什么不退出，这样对我们都好
Why don't you do us both a big favor and quit?
我是个救生员，是的，我是
I'm a rescue swimmer, yes, I am
我来这里援救你们离开这该死的地方
I'm here to pull your ass out of this jam
我跳出直升机，带着绳索
I jump from the helo and swing from the cable
我不是泰山，我是心甘情愿的 并且有能力这样做
I'm not Tarzan I'm just willing and able
用其它的来惩罚我吧，二级军士长
Give me something else, Senior Chief.
三十
Thirty!
三十一
Thirty-one!
三十二
Thirty-two!
三十三
Thirty-three!
三十四
Thirty-four!
三十五
Thirty-five!
三十六
Thirty-six!
停下
Stop. Drop them.
二级军士长来了，起立
Senior Chief's on deck. Pop tall.
乌拉
Oorah!
早上好，各位
Morning, class.
今天我们要学的是
Today we were going to learn
怎么在深海靠近生还者
about how to approach a drowning victim in high seas,
但我想这里有人对生还者不感兴趣
but I think there are some here who aren't interested in that victim.
事实上我觉得这个班里有些人
Fact, I think there's some in this class
对援救他人并不感兴趣
who aren't interested in saving lives at all.
我相信有些人
I believe there are some
对于创造记录非常感兴趣
who are more interested in setting records.
那么今天就是记录日
So today is record day.
5：28
5:28.
把金鱼的名字贴上去
Put one on the board for Goldfish.
哇，他还真快
Wow, he's fast.
他很不错
He's good.
你办到了，伙计! 你做到了，费舍尔!
You got it, man! You got it, Fisch!
另一个记录，记下来，军事长
Another record. Chalk it up, Chief.
- 再来点  - 你是真正的男人
- Get some.  - You are the man!
你们其他人都不配和杰克一起在池子里
You people do not deserve to be in the same pool as Jake.
他打败了你们所有人
He's destroying you.
哇，看他游啊，真快
Wow, look at him go! He's fast!
哇，他真快
Wow, he's fast.
快啊，你在挑战记录 暂时只有一个失败者
Come on, you're all fighting for second. Just first loser.
真有趣
This is fun.
待会我们会发奖品
We'll pass out trophies later.
不可思议
Unbelievable.
要我把这些娘娘腔都赶走吗？
You want me to pull these pansies out?
- 你不会想知道我今天是怎么过的  - 我想知道
- You do not wanna hear about my day.  - Yeah, I do.
那个家伙，朗道
Man, this guy Randall...
他根本不在乎我做的多好 他总是觉得不够好
You know, it doesn't matter what I do. It's just not good enough.
我想他只是希望你变得更好
Well, maybe he's just trying to push you to be better.
你知道，我们老师会鼓励 我们觉得有潜质的学生
You know, we teachers do that to the ones we believe in.
不，他是针对我
No, it's personal with me.
他知道我比他优秀
He knows that I'm better than he was.
我是说，今天我打破了所有他保持的记录
I mean, today, I broke every one of his records.
所有记录都是我的了
I own them all.
并不是所有的
Not all of them.
有一个记录你还没有破
There's one record you won't break.
那是在埃及斯
This is the Aegis.
医疗船支，着火了
Medical ship. Caught on fire.
那真是个梦魇，人们在大火中惊醒
It was a nightmare. People burning in their beds.
本・朗道把所有人都救出来了
And Ben Randall got every one of those people off there,
除了一个人
except for this one guy.
当船开始下沉的时候
And right when the ship started to go down,
他进去找到了这个人
he reaches down and grabs this guy.
当时绞盘卡死了
He's hanging from the cable with this man's life in his hands,
他手上抓住的是那个人的生命
and the winch jams.
在飞回基地的20分钟，那个人一直在尖叫
It's 20 minutes to the base. The man's screaming.
本看着他的眼睛，猜他怎么说？
Ben looks him dead in the eye, and you know what he said?
他说：“我绝不放手”
He said, "I won't let go."
后来呢？
What happened?
他的肩膀脱臼，跟腱全部撕裂
Dislocated his shoulder, tore every tendon in his hand.
但是本没有放手
But he didn't let go.
20分钟，就靠手指拉住缆绳
Twenty minutes, just fingertips.
你如果打破了那个记录，打电话告诉我
You break that record and you give me a call.
我今天过的还算不错
My day was all right.
我想我们应该约会了
So here's my thinking. We should go on a date.
- 好的，那现在我们叫什么来着？  - 不不不
- Well, what do you call this?  - No, no, no.
我是说我想要个真正的约会
I'm talking about, like, a real date.
要有个好餐馆，穿漂亮的衣服
You know, with, like, a nice restaurant, some nice clothes.
我会给你买花
I'll get you some flowers.
我想我们说过这是临时的
I thought we agreed to keep this casual.
只是一块牛排而已
Look, it's one steak. What is...
一块牛排可没有持久的感情纠葛
One steak is not gonna forge some kind of a lasting emotional bond.
我是认真的
I'm serious.
真的吗？
Yeah?
- 是的  - 我也是
- Yeah.  - So am I.
只是一顿晚饭，有什么关系？
It's one dinner. What's it gonna hurt?
好吧，如果你说是一块牛排 我就知道会牵扯到整头牛了
Well, if you ordered a steak, I'd imagine a cow would be involved.
这是什么，纹身吗，2是什么意思？
What do you have, an art gallery over here? What is this "2"?
这让我后面的家伙知道他的位置
It's so the guy behind me knows what place he's coming in.
那这个呢？
What about this one?
这是我高中的队友
That is the initials of the guys on my high school relay team.
酒会之后干的傻事？
A drunken celebration gone wrong?
算是吧
Something like that.
- 那么，我们的约会  - 天啊，只是晚餐，好吗？
- So, about this date.  - God. It's just dinner, right?
不许送花，不能谈论感情问题
No flowers, where we will discuss nothing emotional or important?
我已经完全准备好了
I am fully prepared
当一个小时的芝加哥公牛
to do an entire hour on nothing but the Chicago Bears.
我们可以毫无疑义地做爱
And we can have completely meaningless sex
马上来
immediately afterwards.
你觉得我们第一次约会我就会和你睡吗？
You think I'm gonna sleep with you on our first date?
你说呢
Think again.
你撞到我了
You just head-butted me.
我来教你蛙泳
I'm gonna teach you the breaststroke.
这可复杂了，和蝶泳可不一样
It's pretty complicated, different than that of the butterfly.
我想我睡不着了
I guess I can't sleep.
当然了
Well, of course you can't.
妻子离开你，好友过世
Your wife left you. Your best friend died.
听起来想首该死的乡村音乐
You sound like a damn country song.
如果你有条狗，他现在也会跑开了
If you had a dog, he'd be run over by now.
- 她把离婚书给你了吗？  - 是的
- So, did she send you papers?  - Yeah.
你读了吗？
And did you read them?
不，没有
No, I did not.
好吧，你想过怎么办吗？
Well, you think you might ought to?
你知道，不可能有其它人了
You know, there never was anyone else, Mags.
算了吧，本
Like hell, Ben.
你是个大人物
You're a bigamist.
你已经嫁给海岸警卫队了
You been married to the Coast Guard all along.
肩膀靠过来点
Give me that shoulder.
你还在游只是想证明你还是19岁
You probably swum it out of socket trying to prove you're still 19.
对吗？
Am I right?
我们是什么时候变老的？
When the heck did we get old?
我们一直在变老，本
Hell, I've always been old, Ben.
你知道吗，我不在乎
You know what, though? I don't mind.
我是说，如果肌肉酸痛了 说明我们已经使用过了
I mean, if my muscles ache, it's 'cause I've used them.
如果我现在走不动路
If it's hard for me to walk up them steps now,
那是因为每晚我都走到爱我的人那去
it's 'cause I walked up them every night to lay next to a man who loved me.
我这里满是皱纹
I got a few wrinkles here and there,
因为我经历了无数快乐的日子
but I've laid under thousands of skies on sunny days, yeah.
我在享受生命，我喝酒，抽烟
I look and feel this way, well, 'cause I drank and I smoked,
我生活，爱怜，跳舞，歌唱，流汗
I lived and I loved, and danced, sang, sweat
用自己的方式享受生活
and screwed my way through a pretty damned good life,
如果你问我
if you ask me.
变老不是坏事，本
Getting old ain't bad, Ben.
变老是收获
Getting old, that's earned.
有一天你必须决定
There will come a time when you might have to decide
谁活下来谁死去
who lives and dies out there.
这可不是好差事
It's a terrible responsibility,
但这是你作为救生员必须学会做的
But it is one you will have to make as a rescue swimmer.
事实上
The bigger reality is,
这是你作为一个人
it's also something you're going to have to live with
一定会遇到的情况
as a human being.
你一定会碰到说不的时候
There will come a time when you're going to have to say no.
最重要的是保证自己能活着
The most important person to keep alive is yourself.
你会面对5到20个船员对你说“救我救我”
You'll be facing crews from five to 20, all saying, "Save me, save me."
他们在等待奇迹
They're looking for a miracle.
- 你多大了，霍吉？
- 24  - How old are you, Hodge?  - Twenty-four.
在24岁的年纪，你必须成为那个奇迹
At 24 years old, you have to become that miracle.
你得找到成为奇迹的办法
You have to find a way to be that miracle.
向右看，向前看，向左看
Looking right, looking center, looking left.
乌拉
Oorah!
先生你还好吗？我是海岸警卫队救生员
You okay, sir? I'm a rescue swimmer.
再来一次
Again.
好吧，就这样 休息一下
All right, that's it. Time-out.
- 他每次都很慌张，军士长  - 霍吉, 过来
- Panics every time, Senior.  - Hodge, over here.
嘿
Hey.
你和生还者唯一的区别
The only difference between you and the victim
是你们在水里的态度
is the attitude in which you enter the water.
你得找到面对混乱
You've gotta figure out a way to be calm
冷静下来的办法 明白吗？
in the face of chaos. Do you understand?
这是你的第一次失败，查理
That's your first challenge, Charlie.
再多一次你就走人
One more and you're gone.
- 出来  - 是，二级军士长
- Come out.  - Aye, aye, Senior Chief.
怎么了，费舍尔？
What's up, Big Fisch?
你不必听他的，霍吉
You don't have to take his shit, Hodge.
你知道么，这对你来说太容易了，费舍尔
What do you know? It's so easy for you, Fischer.
是这样吗？
Is that right?
没错
Yeah.
知道吗，你还是没有搞清楚
You know, you don't get it.
你不知道你比我坚强多了
You don't realize that you're tougher than I am.
为什么？
And how's that?
如果我被踢出去了，我可不会回来
Well, if I get kicked out of here, I'm not coming back.
我绝对不会再次回来
I'm definitely not coming back twice.
我是说，你是个坚毅的家伙
I mean, you got guts, man.
是愚蠢
Stupidity.
你来了多久了，伙计？
How long you been here, man?
总共…不知道，第一次10周
Altogether... I don't know, 10 weeks the first time,
- 第二次6周零2天  - 这次是6周
- six weeks, two days the second time...  - Six weeks this time.
所以，你来这儿的时间
So basically, you've been here
比任何一个从这里毕业的人都要久了
longer than anybody that's graduated this place,
但你还不觉得你能毕业
but you don't think you can make it.
打起精神来，伙计
Lighten up on yourself, man.
走吧 我们去喝几杯
Let's go. Let's get a beer.
嘿，等等 你不是 和婚礼上遇到的女孩有约吗？
Hey, wait. Don't you have a date with the girl from the wedding?
是的，但现在还没到9:00 还有时间 把衣服穿上
Yeah, but it's not till 9:00. We got time. Get dressed.
我们走
Let's go.
当你被往下拽的时候
When you go under, when you're pulling on your stroke,
- 移动你的手臂  - 等等，我们去哪里？
- move your hand...  - Wait a minute. Where are we going?
杰克，这是乌贼酒吧 是海军的地头
Jake, that's a squid bar. I mean, there's Navy guys everywhere.
我才不管呢，我们只是喝瓶酒而已
I don't give a shit. A beer's a beer.
你被拖下水的时候，你必须把自己弄出来
When you're pulling through the water, you're gonna pull yourself through.
- 就像，你知道  - 我得迅速
- Like, you know...  - So I'll go fast.
不，你得侧身摆脱，就像这样
No, you wanna lay to your side and pull it like that.
嘿，查理 把那些衣服换掉
Hey, Charlie, you get those fittings replaced
- 在你喝醉之前好吗？  - 是，长官
- before you came off to get tanked up?  - Yes, sir, Captain.
是的，我亲眼看到才相信
Yeah, I'll believe that when I see it.
我们去“A”学校
We go to "A" School,
这是军队里门槛最高的学校
which is the most difficult school in the military.
那儿的淘汰率是，50%吗？
The attrition rate's, like... What is it, 50%?
50%
50%.
- 超过50%  - 超过50
- It's over 50%.  - Over 50.
我们还在这里，因为我们是精英中的精英
We're still here, 'cause we're the best of the best.
当暴风来了港口关闭，知道谁出任务吗？
When storms shut down entire ports, you know who goes out?
是我们
We do.
当飓风…当飓风让海军不能动弹时
When hurricanes... When hurricanes ground the US Navy,
就像那边的小孩子一样 猜猜谁会出任务？
like these little guys over here, guess who goes out?
没错，是我们
That's right, we do.
听着，亲爱的，你得小声点，好吗？
Look, honey, you better keep it down in here, okay?
好的，亲爱的 她叫我“亲爱的”
Okay, honey. She called me "honey."
好的，亲爱的
Okay, honey.
当上帝从天而降
But when God himself reaches down from heaven...
- 他会怎么做，杰克，当他…  - 把房子从地上撕裂
- What does he do, Jake, when he...  - Rips houses off the foundation.
当上帝把房子从地上撕裂，我们出任务
When God himself rips houses off the foundation, we go out,
因为我们是救生员
because we are rescue swimmers,
这是我们的工作，我们干的就是这个
and that is our job, and that's what we do.
你应该重新检查一下罗盘
You might wanna recheck your compass.
这里可不是什么烂海盗来的酒吧
This ain't no puddle pirate bar.
没问题，我们马上就走
No problem, because we were just leaving anyway.
- 坐下，霍吉  - 杰克
- Sit down, Hodge.  - Jake.
- 把酒喝完  - 杰克
- Finish your beer.  - Jake.
对，坐下，霍吉
Yeah, sit, Hodge.
伙计，这是我的啤酒
That's my beer, man.
喝完了吗？
Finished now?
祝你愉快
Must be happy hour.
嘿！
Hey!
后退
Back off.
来这里的都是退休海军
Everyone in this place is retired Navy.
嘿，嘿 我什么时候才能用电话？
Hey. Hey, when do I get that phone call?
我知道我有权力打电话 什么时候给我电话打？
I know I get a phone call. When do I get my phone call?
女士，非常抱歉
Ma'am, I am sorry,
如果20分钟没人来，我可要把桌子给别人了
but if nobody come in 20 minutes, I need the table.
- 好的  - 对不起
- Okay.  - I'm sorry.
好吧
Yeah.
她再也不会和我说话了
She's never gonna talk to me again.
你知道他们会把我们踢出去的，对吗？
You know they're gonna kick us out for this, right?
是的
Yep.
至少他们不会说我们是自己退出的
Least they can't say we quit.
我办不到的 长官说的对，每次我都紧张
I was never gonna make it, anyway. Skinner's right. Panic every time.
伙计，别管长官怎么说
Man, screw Skinner.
我是长官，来挣脱我
I'm Skinner. Break my hold.
嘿，伙计，你在做什么？ 来吧，费舍尔，放开我
Hey, what are you doing, man? Come on, Fischer, get off me.
时间有限，快点挣脱我
Clock's ticking. Break it.
费舍尔，你弄伤我了 费舍尔，放开我，伙计!
Fischer, you're hurting me, man. Fischer, get off me, man!
快点，费舍尔，你弄伤我了 费舍尔，放开！
Come on, Fischer, you're hurting me. Fischer, man, get off!
- 快他妈的挣脱我  - 费舍尔，放开我!
- Break the goddamn hold.  - Fischer, get off me, man!
- 快挣脱，霍吉  - 费舍尔，放开我!
- Break the goddamn hold, Hodge.  - Fischer, get off me!
我说，放开我!
I said, get off me!
好吧
All right.
你在水里的时候就该这样
Now, it's just like that when you're in the water.
好了，现在我们可以走了
Well, now. We could come back.
给你们点时间抽抽烟，说说枕边话什么的
Give you boys time for a smoke and some pillow talk.
你不能把我们踢出去
You can't kick us out.
这叫不守纪律，我们可以把你们踢了
It's called disorderly conduct, and yes, we can.
- 我们没有不及格  - 我们的专业包括遵守纪律
- We didn't fail at nothing.  - Our profession is all about control.
你们这方面都不及格
You both failed miserably in that department.
站在这里
Hold it right there.
- 军士长？  - 进来吧
- Senior?  - Yeah, come in.
他们的开除报告
Their disenrollment records.
酒吧斗殴？
Bar fight?
- 好了，带他们进来  - 军士长
- All right, bring them in.  - Senior.
进来吧
Square it.
这都是我的错，二级军事长 霍吉和这无关
It's all my fault, Senior Chief. Hodge had nothing to do with it.
- 是这样吗，霍吉？  - 没错
- That true, Hodge?  - It's true.
好吧，你解散吧
All right. Fine, you're dismissed.
- 二级军士长，我  - 我说了你已经解散了
- Senior Chief, I was...  - I said that you are dismissed.
走吧
Let's go.
因为我捍卫了海岸警卫队的尊严 你就要踢我走人吗？
You're gonna kick me out for defending the Coast Guard?
海岸警卫队有200年历史
The Coast Guard's been around for 200 years.
我想只有你这样的傻冒 会这样维护它的尊严
I doubt a couple of knuckleheads like yourself are gonna defend it.
坐下
Sit down.
我想和你平静下来平等地谈谈，但是
I've been trying to peel the layers back on you for a while now, and I...
我有一点不明白
I just don't get it.
我是说，这工作对于你这样的人来说
I mean, this kind of work seems a little remedial
似乎只是一种疗伤
for someone like yourself.
你知道，游泳冠军 常春藤每一个学校的奖学金
You know, big swim champ, offer to every lvy League.
你放弃一切到这和我们在一起
You give it all up to be here with us.
- 为什么？  - 我是为了拯救生命，二级军士长
- Why?  - I'm here to save lives, Senior Chief.
我和你的教练谈过了，杰克
I spoke with your coach, Jake.
- 好我的教练谈？  - 是的，我和你的教练谈了
- You spoke with my coach?  - Yeah, I spoke with your coach.
你的档案里有些东西让我很牵挂
Something in your file just kept hanging me up.
你第一年和第二年连续获得州里的冠军
You win the state championship your freshman and sophomore year
但后两年你没再去游
and then you don't swim the next two.
我只是个公立学校毕业的家伙
I'm just a public school guy, so pardon me,
我一直没有意识到，直到看到这些
but it didn't add up until now.
“科科・霍里华，100米混合泳冠军”
"Kirk Holloway, 100-meter medley winner,
“从车窗里甩了出去”
"thrown through the passenger window.
“当场死亡”
"Pronounced dead at the scene.
“艾比・科曼，美国1队，肺穿孔”
"Abe lkeman, first team All-American, lungs crushed.
“卡尔・山多夫，50米自由泳冠军”
"Carl Sandoval, 50-meter freestyle champ,
“送往医院的途中死于内出血”
"made it all the way to the hospital. Died of internal bleeding."
我想你都知道了
I guess you just know everything, then.
我知道失去队友是什么样的
I know what it's like to lose a team.
是吗
Yeah?
生活在一个小镇上
What about living in a small town
别人认为他杀了自己的兄弟
where everyone thinks that you killed their brother
儿子或是最好的朋友，会是什么感觉？
or their son or their best friend?
你知道那是什么感觉吗？
You know about that?
看来小镇上的人相互之间打招呼
Kind of small town where everyone still waves to everyone,
但不和你打招呼？
just not to you?
我读了报告，杰克 当时你的酒精含量为零
I read the report, Jake. Your blood alcohol was zip that night.
我猜是另一个冒失的司机开的车
I'm guessing there was a flip for designated driver.
你却被错怪
You lost.
猜猜就能解决问题？
Guess that just makes it all go away, huh?
不，没有解决任何问题 这只是一场意外
No, it doesn't make it all right. It just makes it an accident.
至少报告上这样说
At least that's how it reads.
那时你才16岁，杰克
You were 16 years old, Jake.
我不是你的牧师，但如果我是，我想
I'm not your priest, but if I was, I think...
我想我不会为难你
I think maybe you'd deserve a pass.
不为难我？
You're giving me a pass?
你以为你知道所有事 其实你什么都不是
You just think you know everything with your psychobabble bullshit.
为什么我在这里？为什么你在这里？
Why am I here? Why are you here?
你太老了只能干这个，你已经快不行了
You're too old to be doing this. You're washed-up here.
你可不想在池子里教小孩，我说的对吗？
You don't wanna be teaching a bunch of kids in a pool. Am I right?
我不在乎你看了什么说了什么
I don't give a shit what you read or who you talked to.
你根本不了解我，你不… 我能管好我自己
You don't know about me! You don't... I have me under control.
我能看出来
I can see that.
我和你唯一的区别是
The only difference between you and me is,
我没有帮在我手上 死去的人穿上衣服，杰克
I don't wear the ones I lost on my arm, Jake.
我知道你的处境，杰克
I know where you're at, Jake.
我也在那儿
I'm there myself.
每天我都会问自己 为什么我是幸存下来的那个人
I ask myself every day why I was the one that survived.
- 然后？  - 然后
- And?  - And...
如果我回答不了自己
And if I can't answer that for me,
我没办法试着向你解释
I'm certainly not going to try and answer it for you.
坐下
Have a seat.
我想让你成为其中一员
I want you to start being a member of this team,
你知道我指的是什么
the team you have now.
你很有天赋，杰克
You have a gift, Jake.
你是到这里来的最棒的队员
You're the best swimmer to come through this program,
不用很久，你能轻松通过的
hands down, by far.
你有整个纪录板去证明
You got a whole record board to prove it.
你知道我看到了什么吗？
But you know what I see when I look at it?
我看到有人足够快能够 第一个游到幸存者身边
I see someone fast enough who's gonna get there first.
我看到有人足够强壮能够支撑到最后
I see someone strong enough who's gonna last.
我看到有人能拯救别人救不了的人
I see someone who can save a life that maybe nobody else could.
你想以你的双手创造荣耀吗？
You really wanna honor the initials on your arm?
那就好好利用你的天赋吧
Then honor your gift.
救每一个你能救到的人，杰克
Save the ones you can, Jake.
其余的，我们得学会放手
The rest, we've gotta let go.
你是说你不会开除我？
Does this mean you're not gonna fail me?
为什么，就为了在酒吧帮助伙伴？
For what, backing up a buddy in a bar?
伙计，比起你我可有过更大的麻烦
Man, I got bigger problems than you.
我不知道你，要是我 我他妈的可要操起酒瓶子揍他了
I don't know about you, but I could use a fucking drink.
喔
Oops.
我今天晚上都在考虑纪录和责任之外的事
I'm gonna consider everything tonight off-record and off-duty.
这个是个邀请
That was an invite.
哦
Oh.
你一定是开玩笑
You gotta be kidding me.
- 他们是怎么称呼你的？  - “烂海盗”，这不是…
- What was it they called you?  - "Puddle pirates," but it's not...
别去了，军士长
I'm way over it, Senior Chief. This is...
- 好吧，看上去可不友善啊  - 我们就喝一杯酒
- Well, it's like sticks and stones.  - Well, we'll just have one beer.
很好，他们喝的烂醉
Great. They're angrier and drunker. Perfect.
嗨，2杯啤酒
Hi. Two beers.
- 你在开玩笑吧  - 我就是这么说的
- You gotta be kidding me.  - That's what I said.
听着，别给我惹事，明白吗？
Look, I don't want any trouble, okay?
他们都不喜欢我们，对吗？
They really don't like us, do they?
不 他们觉得比我们优秀 因为他们是打仗的
No. They think they're better than us because they're combat-oriented.
我们是海岸警卫队，杰克
We're the Coast Guard, Jake.
没有人会赏识我们，除非他们需要我们
Nobody really appreciates us until they need us.
是他吗？
That him?
是的
Yep.
在我们开始流血之前我先问你个问题
So let me ask you a question before we start bleeding.
你救的那么多人…具体数字是多少？
All those saves... What's your real number?
你是想死呢还是傻的可以？
Do you have a death wish, or are you just shit-stupid?
算是犯傻劲吧
I'm gonna go with stupid this time.
- 嗨  - 嗨
- Hi.  - Hi.
这是谁？你老子？
Who's this, your old man?
瞧，我很高兴你还在这儿
You know, I'm really glad you're still here.
- 喔，是吗？  - 是的
- Oh, yeah?  - Yeah.
- 小心后面  - 退下!我说退下
- Behind you.  - Stand down! I said stand down.
我想你们最好快离开
I think you better leave.
好吧
Okay.
走吧，杰克
Come on, Jake.
好吧 坐下，喝杯酒
All right, sit down. Have a beer.
- 这比我想象中的好的多了  - 是的
- That went a lot better than I thought.  - Yeah.
- 那是什么？  - 我不知道
- What the hell was that?  - I don't know.
嘿，我得向你道歉
Hey, I wanted to apologize to you
说你太老了什么的
for what I said earlier about you being old and washed-up now.
你有什么要对我说的吗？
Is there anything you'd like to say to me?
比方说？
Like what?
我不知道，但我对你道歉了
I don't know, but I apologized to you.
我只是觉得，你知道
I just thought that, you know,
你以前可能说过些什么
there might be something you've said or done
那些你可以向我道歉的
that you'd like to apologize to me for.
为什么？
Why?
因为就该是这样的，我…
'Cause that's how it's done. I...
你知道吗，你真是太不会道歉了
You suck at apologies, you know that?
我是说你都没弄明白什么是道歉
I mean, you're missing the whole concept.
- 喂你好？  - 嗨，是我
Hello?  - JAKE: Hi. It's me.
你还好吗？发生什么了？我等了你2个小时
Are you okay? What happened? I mean, I waited for two hours.
嗯 听着，这很复杂
Yeah. No. Look, I'm really sorry. I...
怎么了？
What happened?
真的要说很久了
It's a really long story.
让我…这样说吧
Let me just... Let me put it this way.
这是我这辈子最好也是最坏的一天
It was the best worst night of my life.
好吧，我很高兴有人找到乐子了
Well, I'm glad someone had fun.
明天能见你吗？
Can I see you tomorrow night?
明天有家长会
I have parent-teacher conferences tomorrow.
那后天呢？
What about the next night?
我一周都有家长会
I have parent-teacher conferences all week.
- 你要甩了我吗？  - 不，杰克
You blowing me off?  - EMILY: No, Jake.
我不会这样做的
I wouldn't do that to somebody.
再过几个小时我得出发了 我要睡了
I gotta get up in a couple hours. I gotta go.
- 好的  - 再见
- Yep.  - Goodbye.
好了，你们还都记得该怎么做吧
All right, you know what we briefed on the ground.
和以前一样，我们要一起行动
Same thing. We're gonna stay together.
无论发生了什么事，你们要一起行动
No matter what happens out there, you stay together.
无论要做什么决定，一起行动
Whatever decision you make, you make as a team.
我们训练时从15到20英尺跳下去
We trained to freefall at 15 to 20 feet.
从50尺跳下去，就像跳进混凝土
You fall from 50 feet, it's like hitting concrete.
从80到100尺跳下去，你就没命了
You fall 80 to 100 feet, you die.
嘿，他们走了？
Hey, where they going?
他们会回来的，对吗？
They're supposed to come back for us, right?
我不知道 霍吉，你以前来过这里
I don't know. Well, Hodge, you been here before.
他们会回来的，对吗？
They're gonna come back for us, right?
是的，但是从来没有那么远
Yeah, but I never made it this far.
- 你一定在开玩笑  - 最后一周前没这样练过
- You're kidding.  - Not to the final week.
他们不会回来了
They're not coming back.
- 我们该怎么办？  - 好了，听着
- What do we do?  - All right, listen up.
我们待在一起
We stay together as a group.
没有人会落下，我们是一个团队
Nobody falls behind. We all stay together.
有人落后了，我们就跟在他的后面，好吗？
One guy goes back, we get him back up to the front, okay?
我们是个团队 乌拉
We're a team. Oorah.
- 乌拉  - 乌拉
- Oorah.  - Oorah!
我们走，5506
Let's do it, 5506.
先生，你没事，我是海岸警卫队救生员
Sir, it's okay, I'm with the US Coast Guard.
再来一次
Again.
我是海岸警卫队救生员 我是来救援你的
I'm a Coast Guard rescue swimmer. I'm here to help you.
暂停
Time-out.
全体起立
Class, pop tall.
霍吉,出来吧
Hodge, get yourself to the side of the pool.
是，二级军士长
Aye, aye, Senior Chief.
乌拉
Oorah!
冷静，长官
Easy, Chief.
看来这下吃的还不算太厉害
Guess it was a lucky punch.
霍吉
Hodge!
- 你还好吗，长官？  - 你给我站在那儿!
- You all right, Chief?  - You stay right there!
做的好，查理
Well done, Charlie.
做的好
Well done.
乌拉，长官
Oorah, Chief Skinner.
5506班，“乌拉，霍吉”，数到三
Class 5506, "Oorah, Hodge," on three!
一，二，三
One, two, three.
乌拉，霍吉
Oorah, Hodge!
干的好
Good for you.
把装备都脱掉
Get their gear off.
- 快点，都脱掉  - 把装备脱掉
- Go on, get that gear off.  - Get that gear off!
脱掉!
Get it off!
5506班，如果我失踪了你们会来找我吗？
Class 5506, will you come find me if I am lost?
是的，二级军士长
Yes, Senior Chief!
如果我溺水了你们回来救我吗？
Will you come save me if I am drowning?
是的，二级军士长
Yes, Senior Chief!
我相信你们会的
I believe you would.
我对这个班有很高的期望
I have high hopes for this class.
我对你有很高的期望
I have high hopes for you.
马修・斯托克斯，草原城，乔治亚
Matthew Stokes, Savannah, Georgia.
- 马修，干的好  - 乌拉，长官
Matthew, a job well done. Oorah, Captain.
肯尼斯・惠特利，清水港，佛罗里达
Kenneth Weatherly, Clearwater, Florida.
出去要好好争气
Go out there and do great things.
威廉・霍吉，阿斯托里亚，俄勒冈
William Hodge, Astoria, Oregon.
二级军士长呢？
Where's Senior Chief?
他有个机会重返科迪亚克，他就去了
He had a chance to go back to Kodiak and he took it.
他从来都不想在这里养老
He never had much of a bedside manner.
他可是条水狗，杰克
He's a water dog, Jake,
也不是个半吊子的教官
and as it turns out, not a half-bad teacher.
好运
Best of luck.
雅格布・费舍尔，科迪亚克，阿拉斯加
Jacob Fischer, Kodiak, Alaska.
祝贺你，杰克 让我们为你骄傲
Congratulations, Jake. Make us proud up there.
是，长官
Aye, aye, Captain.
斯歌特・里夫斯，西斯塔，阿拉斯加
Scott Reeves, Sitka, Alaska.
女士们先生们，这是你们的毕业生
Ladies and gentlemen, your graduates.
乌拉
Oorah!
- 祝贺你  - 谢谢
- Congratulations.  - Thanks a lot.
- 干得好，伙计  - 好运
- Good job, guys.  - Good luck.
- 祝贺你  - 谢谢
- Well, congratulations.  - Thank you.
这没关系
It's okay.
我们都知道会是怎么样的，对吗？
We both knew where this was going, right?
只是临时的
Just casual.
没错
Right.
去追求你想得到的
To getting what you've always wanted.
我总想得到更多
And always wanting more.
好好照顾自己，杰克
Take care of yourself, Jake.
- 我得过去了  - 好的
- I gotta go to work.  - Yeah.
再见
Bye.
女士们先生们，欢迎来此
Ladies and gentlemen, welcome to the Rock.
我是威廉・哈德利上校 科迪亚克空军机场负责人
I'm Captain William Hadley, CO of Kodiak Air Station.
- 费舍尔  - 在
- Fischer.  - Yeah, right here.
米特奇会帮你安排的
Mr. Mitcheltree will square you away.
其他人跟着克里斯特森
The rest of you, step up here with Mr. Christiansen.
他会负责帮你们注册
He will process you in.
真不错
Oh, amazing.
他不但保持了良好的体型
Not only does he come back in great shape,
还学会了烹饪
but he still thinks he can cook.
- 你好，杰克 欢迎你来  - 你过的怎么样
- Hello, Jake. Welcome.  - How you doing?
- 很高兴再次见到你  - 你们俩关系不错嘛
- Good to see you again.  - You guys keep it warm here, huh?
很高兴让你知道一顿自在的饭是怎么样的
Glad to know you know where a free meal is.
我们这个周末在斯特卡需要3个人
We need three crews in Sitka for the weekend.
你做好准备
You make sure that happens.
下周二团队会集结
And the stand team arrives here next Tuesday.
和妻子重归于好了吗？
Patch things up with the wife?
搞定那个女孩了吗？
You fix things up with that young lady?
你知道，你还是有机会的
Well, you still have a choice, you know.
嘿，有个问题我在学校的时候想问
Hey, there's a question I wanted to ask you back in school
却没有问
and I didn't.
当你不能拯救所有人的时候
But when you can't save them all,
你选择哪些人活下来呢？
how do you choose who lives?
这对每个人都不一样，杰克
It's probably different for everybody, Jake.
对我来说挺简单的，我只是
Kind of simple for me, though. I just...
我会带走我第一个遇到的 或是他们之中最虚弱的
I take the first one I come to or the weakest one in the group,
我尽可能游的更快
and then I swim as fast and as hard as I can
更持久
for as long as I can.
大海带走其余的人
And the sea takes the rest.
觉得我准备好了吗？
Think I'm ready?
我不再是你的老师了，杰克 我只是你的救生员同事
I'm not your teacher anymore, Jake. I'm just your fellow swimmer.
这不是我想得到的答案
That's not exactly the answer I'm looking for there.
如果我觉得你没准备好 我不会把你丢到白令海峡去
If I did not think you were ready, I would not put you in the Bering Sea.
6030，这是科迪亚克调度中心
6030, this is Kodiak Ops Cent.
我们要中指你们的训练任务
We are diverting your training mission at this time.
有两个年轻的船员困在洞里了
We have two young kayakers swept into the cave
斯特里洞南面1英里处
one mile south of Saltery Cove.
- 报告  - 6030收到
How copy?  - PILO T 1: 6030 copies.
- 终止训练  - 我们得到新任务
- We're diverting at this time.  - We've got a real case now.
好了，伙计们，看到海浪了吗
Okay, guys, that tide's coming in,
有6到8英尺的浪头从北面过来
and we've got six- to eight-foot rollers coming from the north.
军士长，费舍尔跟你去执行任务吗？
Senior, what do you think about taking Fischer with you on this?
我要他跟着我 他已经准备好了
I want him with me. All right? He's good to go.
我觉得进去不是很困难
I don't think it's gonna be a problem sliding in there.
出来的时候会遇上麻烦
I think the problem's gonna be coming back out.
所以我要杰克和我一起去 他可是人力皮划艇
That's why I got Jake with me. Got my human speedboat.
科迪亚克调度中心，我是6030 我们已经到达目的地
Kodiak Ops, this is 6030. We're on-scene at this time.
没有发现幸存者，我们准备入水
No sign of kayakers. I'm taking her down.
舱门打开
Cabin door is open and locked.
有10英尺高的浪头
Those are definitely ten-foot waves.
救生员准备
Swimmer's coming to the door.
记住，好吗？
Remember, all right?
海浪会把你冲到洞口
You got the whole weight of the ocean punching through that opening.
你得计算浪头
You gotta read the hydraulics, gotta count the waves,
然后等着回流
then wait for the flush.
检查救生员
Checking swimmer.
但愿你上课的时候仔细听了
Sure as hell hope you paid attention in class, Speedboat.
救生员入水
Swimmers in the water.
救生员良好
Swimmers okay.
救生员1号和2号进行交流
Swimmer Two is making contact with Swimmer One.
嘿
Hey!
这里!
Over here!
- 这里  - 这里!
- Here.  - Over here!
找到了，3点钟方向
Got them. Three o'clock.
这边
Right here.
我们是海岸警卫队救生员 我们来救援你们
We're rescue swimmers. We're gonna get you out of here.
真不敢相信你们真的来了
Can't believe you guys actually got here.
把手给我
Give me your hand.
只有你们两个？
Just the two of you?
是的 他的手伤的很重
Yeah, yeah. His arm's hurt real bad.
好的
All right.
1号救生员，有两个幸存者 准备放下救生篮
Swimmer One. I got two survivors. It's gonna be a basket pickup here.
明白
Roger.
这儿受伤了？
Broken here?
你带他先走，把他放到救生篮里
You take him first. Get him in the basket.
我和还有一个人跟在你后面
I'll follow with the other one right behind you.
- 明白吗？  - 好的
- You got that?  - Yeah.
- 明白了吗？  - 是的，明白
- You got it?  - Yeah, yeah.
我这样慢慢带着你，好吗？
All right. I'm gonna lower you down in here, all right?
- 好的  - 放松，伙计，我抓着你
- Okay.  - Relax, buddy. I got you.
好的
All right.
- 你跟着我  - 好的
- You're with me.  - Okay.
我不太会游泳
I don't swim so good.
- 你不太会游泳？  - 是的
- You don't swim so good?  - No, sir.
没关系，我游的很好，我跟着你
It's okay. I swim pretty good. All right, on your back.
- 等等，我们有小船坐吗？  - 我就是小船
- Wait. Are we gonna take the boat?  - I'm the boat.
等等，等等
Wait. Wait, wait, wait.
- 我还没准备好，我不能…  - 嘿
- I'm not ready! I can't...  - Hey!
- 等等，等等  - 冷静
- Wait, wait, wait...  - Settle down!
有些不对头
Something's not right.
1号救生员回到洞里了
Swimmer One's going back to the cave.
怎么了？
What happened?
他撞到了木头
He hit a log.
什么？你在…
What? What are you...
什么…
What...
- 他死了，杰克  - 他没有
He's gone, Jake.  - JAKE: He's not.
他只是撞到了头
He's just got a head laceration.
我们走，快走
Here we go. Come on.
我们走
Let's go.
我们走!
Let's go!
二级军士长朗道!注意力集中
Senior Chief Randall! Lock it in.
这只是简单的物理学
It's simple physics.
只要等着回流就行了，对吗？
We're just gonna time the flush, all right?
好的
All right.
你下令吧，救生员
You call it, Swimmer.
现在!
Now!
嘿，我知道你很疲倦，好吗 我知道你很累
Hey, I know you're tired, okay? I know you feel tired right now.
但你得把眼睛睁开，好吗
But you need to keep your eyes open, okay?
好吗？嘿，你来和他谈谈
All right? All right? Hey, I need you to keep talking to him.
- 你继续和他说  - 好的
- You keep talking to him.  - Okay.
军事长 军事长!
Senior. Senior!
你能帮我把这个打开吗？
Can you open these up for me?
我要你一个一个给我
One by one, I want you to hand them to me.
往上看
Reyes!
他没事
He's fine.
这里，伙计 这里
Right here, buddy. Right here. Okay?
- 好的  - 这里
- Okay.  - Right here.
- 罗伯特  - 我没事
Robert!  - I'm okay.
他的右臂有骨裂
He's got a compound fracture in his right radius.
我们试着固定住
We tried to stabilize that a little bit.
用的这个
We put a collar on this one,
但只是临时性的
but it's more precautionary than anything.
谢谢
Thank you.
他可能有些轻微脑震荡
This one's possibly a little bit concussive.
我们一路上都在帮他们检查
We checked their vitals the whole way back.
他们都有些体温过低 但会好起来的
They're both mildly hypothermic, but I think they'll come around.
非常感谢
Thank you so much.
不客气
You're welcome.
这是可能会发生的，本
It happens, Ben.
不该是我，不该是这样的
Not to me. Not like that.
我要你在我面前把这个签了
I want you to sign them in front of me.
你为什么不再考虑考虑呢？
Why don't you take some time and think about it?
不 这…
No. It's...
结束了 签了它吧
It's over. Just sign them.
拜托了
Please.
每个人都可能出现这样的情况
Could've happened to anyone.
也许吧
Maybe.
但是如果再发生了怎么办？
But what if it happens again? What then?
他只用缝几针就行了，不会有事的
Kid got a couple stitches. He's gonna be fine.
我们把他救出来了
We got him out of there.
不，是你救的
No, you did.
你今天表现很好
You were strong out there today.
我为你感到骄傲
I was proud of you.
你准备接下来做什么呢？
What are you gonna do?
有朋友曾经建议我去钓鱼
Friend of mine once suggested fishing.
我想我会接受他的提议
Think I might take his advice.
钓鱼？
Fishing?
是的
Yeah.
我们这样的人不钓鱼的
Guys like us don't go fishing.
我以前好像听说过
Where have I heard that before?
军士长，你走之前
Senior, before you go,
我想知道一件事
I gotta know one thing.
正确的数字是多少？
What's your real number?
Twenty-two.
２２？
Twenty-two?
还不坏 不是200，不是…
That's not bad. It's not 200. It's not...
22是我没救到的数字，杰克
Twenty-two's the number of people I lost, Jake.
我只记这个数字
Only number I kept track of.
把嘴里的海腥味去去
Keeps the sea out of your mouth.
嘿
Hey.
嗨
Hi.
你重新开始画画了？
You started painting again?
是的，可以有点事做
Yeah. Great light up there.
你知道
You know,
那个电话的事我得向你道歉，海伦
I wanna apologize for the phone calls, Helen.
我该给你空间的
I should've given you your space.
你觉得忽然出现在这里
And you felt showing up here unannounced
是最好的办法来沟通那件事吗？
was the best way to communicate that?
嘿
Hey.
- 请你…  - 本
- Please just...  - Ben.
我要你保存它，连同这个
I want you to have it, along with these.
我签了名
I signed them.
为什么是现在？
Why now?
我有…我以前有一次任务
I had a... I had a case a while back.
你知道的，有一对夫妻溺水了
You know, a couple was drowning.
但当我赶到那儿的时候
By the time I got there,
他丈夫正把他的妻子往下拽
the husband was dragging his wife under,
只是想让自己浮起来
just trying to stay afloat.
纯粹的生存本能
Pure survival instinct.
这让我…
It took me...
让我用了很长时间才意识到 其实那个人就是我
Took me a long time to understand that that man was me.
哦，可恶的，又来了
Oh, man. Oh, doggone it.
对不起
Sorry.
你要接听吗？
Aren't you gonna answer that?
我不再是个救生员了，海伦
I'm not a rescue swimmer anymore, Helen.
再见，亲爱的
Bye, baby.
注意
Lock it up.
一艘75英尺长的渔船求救
We have a 75-foot fishing vessel in distress,
在深海区域船进水
taking on water in high seas.
船失控了有4人在船上
She's dead in the water with four souls onboard.
抽水泵无法持续工作
With its dewatering pumps unable to keep up,
现在的问题不是船会不会沉 而是何时沉没
it's not a matter of if this thing is going down, but when.
绑紧一点 加把劲
Tighten her down! We gotta secure her.
遇到这样的情况你必须说不
There will come a time when you're going to have to say no.
当你面对5到20个船员对你说“救我救我”
You'll be facing crews from five to 20, all saying, "Save me, save me."
他们在等待奇迹
They're looking for a miracle.
在24岁的年纪
At 24 years old,
你得想办法成为那个奇迹
you have to find a way to be that miracle.
一切正常 我们要开始实施救援了
Sounds good. We'll plan our free-fall deployment to the water.
- 准备好了吗，杰克？  - 是的
- Are you good with that, Jake?  - Yeah, copy that.
如果我们要把你放下去 只能放在峰头上
Okay, if we have to put you in, we're gonna get you in upswell
让海浪把你带到船那边去
and let the waves take you down to the boat.
- 准备好了吗  - 是的
- Are you good with that?  - Roger.
我们只有20分钟
We're only gonna have about 20 minutes on-scene,
- 动作快一点  - 明白
- so we gotta be quick.  - Copy that.
我看到渔船了 2点钟方向，50米左右
All right, I got the vessel in sight. Two o'clock, about 50 meters.
舱门开启
Cabin door open and locked.
救生员准备
Pre-rescue checklist for free-fall deployment.
哇！船刚才吃了个大浪
Whoa, whoa! Boat just took a wave, sir.
一个人被冲到船边上了
One appears to have gone on the edge.
他挂在货网上了
He's hanging from the cargo net.
我们得把救生员放下去
We need to get our swimmer down there.
电脑显示风速60节
Computer's showing 60 knots...
别管电脑怎么说了
Going off com.
救生员准备
Prepare for a free-fall deployment of the rescue swimmer.
救生员再次检查
Rescue checklist, part two.
救生员准备完毕
Swimmer's getting ready.
检查完毕 救生员准备入水
Rescue checklist complete. Swimmer's coming out.
明白，检查救生员
Roger that. Check swimmer.
救生员准备完毕，检查
Swimmer's at the door, sir. Checking swimmer.
准备好了？
Swimmer ready?
上帝会保佑你的
God help you if you ain't, boy.
救生员下水了
Swimmer's away.
救生员情况良好 他朝渔船游过去了
Swimmer's okay. He's heading towards the vessel.
他切浪切的真不错
All right, he's cutting through those waves pretty good.
他接近船支了
That's it. He's approaching the vessel.
已经上船了，长官
He's at the boat, sir.
伙计，见到你太好了
Man, are we glad to see you!
科迪亚克调度中心，6034号呼叫
Kodiak Ops, rescue 6034.
费舍尔到船上了，但是船的情况很糟糕
Fischer's onboard, but vessel is compromised.
进了很多水，恐怕支持不了多久了
Taking on lots of water. May not hold much longer.
随时报告最新进展
Stand by for further.
船上有多少人？有没有人受伤？
How many guys you got on here? Is anybody injured?
一共4个人
I got four guys.
他的腿断了
This guy's got a broken leg.
船长在里面，他在试着发动抽水泵
The skipper's down below. He's trying to start the pumps.
- 好的，他先走  - 好的
- All right, he's gonna go up first.  - All right.
科迪亚克，科迪亚克 这是6304
Kodiak Ops, Kodiak Ops, this is rescue 6034.
有三人受伤 船里还有一人
There's three onboard with injuries, one more down below.
你想让我怎么做？
What do you want me to do?
你们帮忙把他放进来
You there, help me get him around in here.
- 把他放进来  - 好的
- Bring him on in.  - All right.
救生篮上升中
Basket is on its way up.
系好安全带
Strap in. Strap in!
船长在里面，甲板上没有人了
The captain's down below, and there's one other man on deck.
我去救他，你绑好自己，不要挡路
Help him out. Strap yourself in. Get out of the way.
重复一遍，船就要沉了，给你8分钟
I repeat, the boat's going down fast. Eight minutes to bingo.
好的，快点，进到篮子里
All right, come on, get in the basket.
收到起吊信号
I have the ready-for-pickup signal.
扶好
Hold on.
1号救生员，1号救生员，快进来
Swimmer One, Swimmer One, come in.
救生员6034
Rescue swimmer, 6034.
费舍尔 进来，费舍尔
Fischer. Come in, Fischer.
1号救生员，1号救生员 进来
Swimmer One, Swimmer One, come in.
- 这是1号救生员  - 收到，1号救生员，继续
This is Swimmer One.  - Roger that, Swimmer One. Go ahead.
救生员1号，船里还有1个人，我去救他出来
Swimmer One. I got one down below. I'm gonna go down there.
救生员1号，我们只剩7分钟了
Swimmer One, be advised we've got seven minutes to bingo.
我下去了
I'm going down.
- 船长？  - 是我
Captain?  - CAPTAIN: Yeah!
船长？
Captain?
船长！我是救生员 我来帮你出去
Captain! I'm a rescue swimmer. I'm here to help you out.
你的腿卡住了还是断了？
Your leg is jammed in here? Or is it just closed...
我的整条腿
It's the whole leg!
我想要放开离合器，但是被卡住了
I tried to free the clutch and got stuck.
这是1号救生员
This is Swimmer One.
我在引擎室找到船长了，他的腿卡住了
I got the captain down here in the engine room. He's stuck.
我们需要一点时间
We're gonna be a little bit.
1号救生员，我们没有时间了
Swimmer One, we're about out of time.
船就要下沉了，我们还有2分钟
That boat's listing bad, and we're two minutes to bingo.
我不会丢下他的
I ain't leaving here without him.
派别人来援救我们，我要看着他
Send somebody back for us, 'cause I'm staying down here with him.
不行，1号救生员 我们要你尽快上来
Negative, Swimmer One. We need you topside ASAP.
1号救生员，6034
Swimmer One, 6034.
科迪亚克，这是6034
Kodiak Ops, Kodiak Ops, this is 6034.
我们现在返回
Be advised we are RTB at this time.
我们把救生员留在现场
We are leaving the rescue swimmer on-scene.
重复一遍，我们把救生员留在现场
I say again, we are leaving our rescue swimmer on-scene.
我们还有直升机吗？
Who do we have left in the shop?
08号可以，但是没有救生员
08's all we've got left, sir, but no crew.
- 好的，快去启动  - 是，长官
- All right, get her online.  - Yes, sir.
上尉，我们准备出发
Lieutenant Krauss, suit up. We're handling this.
我要一个救生员
I need a swimmer.
别担心
Don't worry.
不，不会的，他们会把他救起来的
No, no, they'll get him.
别担心！别担心
Don't worry! Don't worry.
我们走
Here we go.
挺住，挺住
Hold on. Hold on.
- 准备好回家了吗  - 是的，伙计
- Ready to go home?  - Yeah, man.
船长 船长!
Captain. Captain!
- 可以出发了吗，上尉？  - 是的，长官
Are we cleared in, Lieutenant?  - KRAUSS: Aye, aye, Captain.
很好
Outstanding.
1号救生员，我是6008
Rescue Swimmer One, this is 6008.
能听见吗？
Do you read?
1号救生员，我是6008 能听见吗？
Come in, Rescue Swimmer One. 6008. Do you read?
回话，杰克
Come on, Jake, be there.
舱门已打开
Cabin door's coming open. Cabin door's open and locked.
好的，就在那里，甲板上没有人
All right, right there. Right side. Nobody onboard.
好的，我能看到
All right. I see what I want.
把我放下去，放到右边的角上
Just get me down. The right-hand corner.
当心别碰到绳索
Try to avoid the rigging.
救生员要求放到右边的角上
Okay, swimmer requests aft right-hand corner.
右边的角上
Aft right-hand corner.
好的，就这么办
Okay, this is what we're gonna do.
救生员准备，第二部分
Start a rescue checklist, part two,
救生员装备检查
for a harness deployment of the rescue swimmer.
- 不要拖拉绳索  - 明白，备用泵启动
- No trail line...  - Roger that. Backup pump is on.
好的，我们要升起100英尺
All right, we'll do the hoist at 100 feet.
明白
Roger that.
科迪亚克，科迪亚克，6208呼叫
Kodiak Ops, Kodiak Ops, rescue 6028.
6208，允许行动
Rescue 6028, Kodiak Ops. Go ahead.
救生员准备完毕，检查完毕
Swimmer's ready. Load-checking swimmer.
救生员准备出仓
And load check complete. Swimmer's going out the door.
救生员出仓 救生员在下降
Swimmer's out the door. Swimmer's on his way down.
海岸警卫队直升机，收到请回话
Coast Guard helo, do you copy?
海岸警卫队直升机，我是救生员1号
Coast Guard helo, this is Rescue Swimmer One.
收到请回话
Do you copy?
向前偏右40度
Forward, right 40.
向前偏右30度，注意高度
Forward, right 30. Watch your altitude.
明白
Roger.
停，绳索摩坏了，绳索摩坏了
Hold. I have a fouled cable. Fouled cable.
解开绳索
Paying out slack.
海岸警卫队直升机，我是救生员1号
Coast Guard helo, this is Swimmer Number One!
我在引擎室 舱室就要被淹没了
I'm in the engine room, and the hold of the boat is filling up!
- 他在试着解开绳索  - 加油
- He's trying to free the cable.  - Come on.
好了，绳索已解开，绳索已解开
Okay, cable free. Cable free.
好样的
Attaboy.
绳索解开，这里有些磨损
Cable's free, and I got a fray right here.
还可以用，还可以用 我就就指望它了
It's still good. It's still good. I can use it. It's all we got.
好的，很好
All right, good.
向后偏左一些，长官
Go back and left, Captain.
向后偏左，明白
Back and left. Roger that.
杰克
Jake.
加油
Come on.
杰克
Jake!
杰克？
Jake?
军士长 军士长，是你吗？
Senior? Senior, is that you?
金鱼
Goldfish!
门上的锁我都检查过了，就是松不开，卡住了
I checked all the locks on the door. I can't get them loose. They're stuck.
我知道，我知道是什么问题
l know. l see the problem.
军士长，马上就淹满了
It's filling up, Senior Chief!
二级军士长，把我弄出去!
Senior Chief! Get me out of here!
我几乎被淹没了!你得把门打开!
I'm almost submerged! You gotta get the door open!
撑住，杰克
Hold on, Jake.
军士长!船长在那边
Senior! The captain's body!
我们得放弃他了
We gotta let him go. Come on.
杰克，他已经死了
Jake, he's gone!
杰克!
Jake!
救生员都出来了
I got both swimmers coming out.
- 两个救生员都能看见  - 好的，我看到他们了
- Both swimmers are in sight.  - All right, I got them.
钩子已放下
Hook is going down.
偏右40，钩子下落中
Let's go forward, right 40. Hook is halfway down.
我们要用钩子连在一起
I'm hooking into you.
我们只有一次机会
We're only gonna get one shot at this.
我钩好了
I'm in.
我也好了
I'm in!
我还以为你会去钓鱼
I thought you were going fishing.
那你说这是什么？
What do you call this?
哇
Whoa.
绳索要断了，撑住，撑住!
The cable's starting to part! The cable! Hold, hold, hold!
撑住，快把他们拉上来
Okay, hold right there. Hold. I'm bringing them up.
我们得解开它
I gotta jam this cable into the drum.
你在做什么？ 你在做什么？
What are you doing? What are you doing?
想都不要想
Don't even think about it.
这支撑不了我们两个
It's not gonna hold us both.
什么…
What...
会的，可以的 别干傻事
Yes, it will. Don't! Lt'll hold!
军士长落下去!
Senior fell. Senior fell!
杰克拉住他了 杰克拉住他了
Jake's got him. Jake's got him.
我得把他们拉上来
I gotta get them up.
我不会放弃的！
I won't let go!
我知道
I know.
军士长!
Senior!
放开我!
Lower me down!
他掉下去了，掉下去了 朗道要掉到水里去了!
He just fell! He just fell! Randall fell! Hit the water!
放开我
Lower me down!
他掉进水里了，被浪头打到了 只看到船的残片
He's in the water. Been hit by a wave, full debris.
- 放我下去!  - 不行!
- Put me down!  - I can't!
你得把我放下去!
You gotta lower me down now!
让我下去!
Get me out of here!
- 放我下去!  - 不行!
- You gotta lower me down!  - I can't!
让我跳下去
I'll free-fall!
你下去就上不来了 我不能损失两个人
If I do, you don't come back. I can't! I can't lose two!
损失救生员!损失救生员!
Lost swimmer. Lost swimmer.
他看到绳索快断了 他就放手了
He saw the cable coming apart. He just let go.
他从80或90的高度掉下去
He was about 80, 90 feet up, sir.
他没有上来，我没有看到他
He didn't come up. I don't see him.
打开远光灯
Flash landing hover lights.
注意无线电
Monitor the radio, sir.
寻找照明棒，闪光灯，一切东西 他掉在浪头里
Look for flares, strobes, anything. He fell right in the debris.
损失救生员，损失救生员
Lost swimmer. Lost swimmer.
海岸警卫队
The Coast Guard conducted
为一个人做了历史上
one of the largest search-and-rescue missions
最大规模的搜救行动
for a single man in its history,
但一直没有找到二级军士长 本・朗道的尸体
but the body of Senior Chief Ben Randall was never found.
我很抱歉，海伦
I'm sorry, Helen.
我们尽了最大努力了
There's nothing more we can do.
是什么造就了传奇？
What makes a legend?
是一个人在活着的时候做了什么？
Is it what someone did when they were alive...
朗道从来都不太在意这种事情
Randall never was much for this sort of thing.
或者在他死去还被别人惦记？
Or how they're remembered after they're gone?
有些人相信
Some people actually believe
二级军士长游到了阿留申群岛
Senior Chief made the swim to the Aleutian Islands.
他在某个海滩
He's standing on a distant beach somewhere
手上拿着钓竿
with a fishing pole in his hand.
几个星期后我得到了答案
But I found my answer a couple weeks later.
他在哪儿？
Where is he?
伙计，那边没有人了
There's nobody else out there, man.
不，他在那儿
No, he was there.
他一直在我身边
He was with me the whole time.
他说他会等到救援到来
He said he would hold on till help arrived.
他从不放弃
He never let go.
传说在水下有个传奇人物
There's a legend of a man who lives beneath the sea.
他是个捞人的
He is a fisher of men,
给了所有落伍者希望
a last hope for all those who have been left behind.
他是个守护神
He is known as the Guardian.
本・朗道总是说生命就是不断地做选择
Ben Randall always said life is about making choices.
最后，他自己的决断帮我做了决定
In the end, by making his, he helped me make mine.
什么会让你难忘？
What do you remember?
你身上的气味是什么样的？ 你看起来怎么样？
What did you smell? What did you see?
这会让你怎样
How did this make you
感觉？
feel?
我马上就回来
I'll be right back.
你来这里做什么？
What are you doing here?
我对你撒了谎
I lied to you.
我做不到临时的
I can't do casual.